Fuck Wolverine.
Au diable Wolverine.
First, he rides my coattails with the R rating.
D'abord, il m'imite avec sa cote pour adultes.
Then the hairy motherfucker ups the ante by dying.
Ensuite, le sale poilu hausse la mise en mourant.
What a dick.
Quel enfoirי !
Well, guess what, Wolvie?
Devine quoi, Wolvie.
I'm dying in this one, too.
Dans ce film-ci, je meurs א mon tour.
To understand why I took a cat-nap on 1,200 gallons of high-test fuel...
Pourquoi ai-je fait la sieste sur 4 500 litres de diesel hautement explosif ?
I need to take you back to the dewy slopes of six weeks ago.
Pour le comprendre, retournons dans le bon vieux temps, il y a six semaines.
I'd gone international, taking out mass murderers,
Je parcourais la planטte pour יliminer des assassins,
gangsters, unspeakable monsters.
des mafieux, des monstres innommables.
People nobody would touch. Except me.
Des gens que personne n'ose toucher. Sauf moi.
I'm gonna touch them all over.
Je vais les toucher partout.
Hey, it's Gail calling. Love the shiny suit.
Salut, c'est Gail. J'adore le brillant.
Really brings out the sex trafficker in your eyes.
ַa met en valeur vos yeux d'exploiteur sexuel.
Whatever they're paying, I'll double it.
Je vous donne le double de ce qu'ils vous paient.
I don't speak Cantonese, Mister...
Je ne parle pas cantonais, monsieur...
Well, I'm not even gonna attempt that. But I did take 8th grade Spanish, so...
Je n'essaierai mךme pas. Mais j'ai fait un an d'espagnol au secondaire.
Where is the library?
Oש se trouve la bibliothטque ?
Which literally translates to...
ַa se traduit littיralement par...
I don't bargain, pumpkin fucker.
Je ne nיgocie pas, baiseur de citrouilles.
I'll take a cranberry-grapefruit vodka.
Une vodka pamplemousse et canneberge.
I know it's called a Sea Breeze. Don't make me say it.
Un Sea Breeze, je sais. Ne me le fais pas dire.
Hit it, Dolly.
Musique, Dolly.
Taking the hands out of the guns of the criminals!
Dיsarmons-les une main א la fois !
Do not go in there!
ַa pue, lא-dedans !
Oh, God! Oh, God, time out! Time out!
Mon Dieu ! Temps d'arrךt ! Temps d'arrךt !
Cut. Got bad guy blood, right in my open eye.
Coupez. J'ai reחu du sang de mיchant dans l'il.
That's so gross.
C'est dיgotant.
Fuck.
Merde.
Scoutmaster Kevin?
Kevin, le maמtre scout ?
Too exotic?
Trop exotique ?
My world tour brought me home to this guy, Sergei Valishnikov.
Ma tournיe mondiale m'a ramenי chez moi pour traquer Sergei Valishnikov.
But we'll get to him in a moment. 'Cause I know what you're thinking.
On en reparlera dans un instant. Je sais ce que vous pensez.
"I'm so glad I left the kiddos at home."
"Heureusement, les enfants sont א la maison."
But that's where you'd be wrong.
Vous vous trompez.
That babysitter of yours is high as fuck right now...
Votre gardienne est gelיe comme une balle,
and, believe it or not, Deadpool 2 is a family film.
et Deadpool 2 est un film familial, croyez-le ou non.
True story.
Sיrieusement.
And every good family film starts with a vicious murder.
Et chaque bon film familial commence par un meurtre cruel.
Bambi, The Lion King, Saw 7.
Bambi, Le roi lion, Dיcadence VII.
Holy shit pickles! That guy's on fire.
Bon Dieu ! Il est en flammes.
That's not CGI, folks. He's actually on fire.
Pas d'effets spיciaux. Il brle pour vrai.
Yeah. You know I get paid to take out bad guys, right?
J'ai dit qu'on me payait pour יliminer des mיchants.
But this guy? He was one of the worst of 'em.
Mais lui ? C'יtait un des pires.
Hurry up and open this fucking door, and let's kill this motherfucker!
Vite, ouvre cette foutue porte ! On va le tuer, l'enfoirי !
So gross.
Dיgotant.
A panic room? Really?
Une chambre forte ? Vraiment ?
Can you come out?
Peux-tu sortir ?
I really have to go. It's my anniversary.
C'est mon anniversaire de mariage. Je dois filer.
Over and over, I hear people say, "I just don't have enough confidence."
Les gens rיpטtent : "Je manque de confiance en moi."
Listen, confidence is not something you have.
La confiance en soi, ce n'est pas innי. On la crיe.
And you can create it at any moment in time.
On peut la crיer א tout moment.
A sense of confidence is nothing but a sense of power within yourself...
Qu'est-ce que la confiance ? La puissance intיrieure,
a sense of certainty that you can pull something off.
la conviction de pouvoir rיussir.
Start the car! Start the fucking car! Dopinder!
Dיmarre ! Dopinder !
Start the fucking car!
Dיmarre la foutue voiture !
Oh, I shit my pants.
J'ai chiי dans ma culotte.
Actually, that may have been me.
En fait, c'יtait peut-ךtre moi.
Oh, mission accomplished?
Oh, mission accomplie ?
Well, in a George W. sort of way.
Dans le genre George W., oui.
Fucker can't stay in a panic room forever.
Le salaud finira par sortir.
You're living the dreams, DP.
Vous menez la vie rךvיe, DP.
It has been quite the run, Dopinder, and who'da thought?
Quelle aventure, Dopinder ! Qui l'et cru ?
Now I'm talked about in the same sentence as Jesus.
On parle de moi et de Jיsus dans la mךme phrase.
Passion of the Christ, then me. At least domestically.
La passion du Christ, puis moi. Au pays, du moins.
We beat them overseas, where there's no such thing as religion.
On a fait mieux א l'יtranger, oש il n'y a pas de religion.
I do want to live the dreams, Pool Boy.
C'est la vie que je veux, Pool Boy.
Taxiing is not as sexy as it looks.
Le taxi, c'est moins sexy qu'on le croit.
- I want to fill my... - Pockets?
- Je veux combler... - Tes coffres ?
What's your poison? A little cokey cokey?
C'est quoi, ta faiblesse ? La poudre ?
Can't maintain an erection without buying shoes online?
Incapable de bander sans magasiner en ligne ?
I've never experienced that last one. Talk to me, Goose.
ַa ne m'est jamais arrivי. Je t'יcoute, Goose.
I was going to say "soul". I want to fill my soul.
J'allais dire "mon גme". Combler mon גme.
I want to belong to something, like you, Pool, sir.
Je veux faire partie de quelque chose de grand.
Dopinder...
Dopinder...
you never cease to surprise me.
Tu ne cesses jamais de m'יtonner.
You know, the depth of your heart is extraordinary.
Ton cur est d'une profondeur remarquable.
We all need a sense of belonging. We all need a genuine sense of home.
On cherche tous l'appartenance. On veut tous se sentir chez soi.
- A place in this world. - I want to become a contract killer.
- tre א sa place. - Je veux devenir assassin.
I'm sorry. What did you say?
Pardon, quoi ?
Remember when I kidnapped Bandhu and threatened him with great violence?
Rappelez-vous quand j'ai enlevי Bandhu et que je l'ai menacי.
You kind of killed him.
Tu l'as un peu tuי.
And then remember the movie Interview with the Vampire?
Rappelez-vous le film Entretien avec un vampire.
Don't want to.
Je ne veux pas.
When Tom Cruise fed 10-year-old Kirsten Dunst blood for the first time...
Quand Tom Cruise fait boire du sang א la petite Kirsten Dunst
and she looked up at his smooth, handsome face and said...
et qu'elle lטve les yeux vers son visage lisse et beau en disant :
"I want some more."
"J'en veux encore."
Pool, picture me, a 10-year-old Kirsten Dunst.
Pool, imaginez-moi en petite Kirsten Dunst.
I'll never not picture that.
ַa restera gravי dans ma tךte.
But I can't wait to never speak of this, as soon as possible.
J'ai hגte de ne plus jamais en parler le plus vite possible.
We're here.
On y est.
You're my Tom Cruise!
Vous ךtes mon Tom Cruise !
And you're my Kristen Dunst! Kristen? Kirsten?
Tu es ma Kristen Dunst ! Kristen ? Kirsten ?
Sorry I'm late.
Pardon du retard.
There was a bunch of handicapable children stuck in a tree...
Il y avait un tas d'enfants handi-capables dans un arbre
and I had to...
que j'ai...
You're right. I was fighting a caped badass.
D'accord. Je luttais contre un mיchant א cape.
But then we discovered his mom is named Martha, too.
Mais sa mטre א lui s'appelait Martha aussi.
No.
Non.
Traffic?
Un embouteillage ?
Kiss me like you miss me, Red.
Embrasse-moi comme si je t'avais manquי.
Well, come here.
Approche, alors.
I'm gonna shower and get out of this suit.
Je vais me doucher et enlever ce costume.
Don't you want your surprise?
Tu ne veux pas ta surprise ?
Do I look like a patient burn victim?
J'ai l'air d'un grand brlי ?
I got one for you, too.
J'en ai une pour toi aussi.
Happy anniversary, baby.
Bon anniversaire de mariage.
Open, open, open.
Allez, ouvre.
Skee-Ball token.
Un jeton de fךte foraine.
Our first date.
Notre premier rendez-vous.
Yup.
Oui.
That's genuine, high-grade lead.
C'est du plomb de premiטre qualitי.
I'll keep it forever.
Je le garderai א jamais.
Thank you, baby.
Merci, mon amour.
- Open yours. - All right, all right.
- Ouvre le tien. - D'accord.
That's just the most beautiful thing that I've...
Je n'ai jamais rien vu d'aussi...
I don't know what this is.
Je ne sais pas c'est quoi.
My IUD.
Mon D.I.U.
A bomb?
C'est dangereux ?
No, dick for brains. My birth control device.
Mais non, idiot. C'est un contraceptif.
What, you mean that your...
Tu veux dire que...
Baby factory's open for business.
L'usine א bיbיs est ouverte.
Oh, my God!
Mon Dieu !
Oh, my God! I want a boy!
Je veux un garחon !
Or a little girl! Definitely one or the other!
Ou une fille ! Un ou l'autre !
And I want our kid to have only one name.
Et je veux que notre enfant ait un seul nom.
Like Cher or Todd.
Comme Cher ou Todd.
You gotta pump a baby in me first, cowboy.
D'abord, tu dois me faire un bיbי.
Yes, I do.
Oh que oui.
Let's watch some porn and show that bed who's boss.
Regardons un porno et cassons le lit.
Let's do that.
Faisons חa.
Papa...
Papa...
Can you hear me?
Peux-tu m'entendre ?
Papa, can you see me?
Papa, peux-tu me voir ?
Does this song sound familiar to you?
Tu connais cette chanson ?
May.
May.
Connor, if it's a boy. May, if it's a girl.
Connor pour un garחon. May pour une fille.
So weird. Family was always an F-word to me.
C'est bizarre. Pour moi, "famille" יtait un gros mot.
My pile of shit father took off and bailed.
Mon salaud de pטre nous a abandonnיs.
I mean, it's not like I have a lot of strong role models
Je n'ai pas beaucoup de bons modטles dont m'inspirer pour Todd.
Hey. Look at me.
Regarde-moi.
You are not your father.
Tu n'es pas ton pטre.
Besides...
En plus...
I will never, ever let our child be named Todd.
Je n'accepterai jamais que notre fils s'appelle Todd.
But here's the thing, isn't that how it always works?
Mais dis-moi, n'est-ce pas toujours ainsi ?
Like in Star Wars, men are destined to become their father...
Dans La guerre des יtoiles, les hommes sont destinיs א devenir leur pטre
and then have consensual sex with their sister?
et א avoir une relation consensuelle avec leur sur.
I think you missed big, big chunks of that movie.
Je crois que tu as ratי une bonne partie du film.
No, I'm pretty sure Luke nailed her.
Non, je suis sr que Luke l'a sautיe.
Baby, that's Empire.
Tu confonds avec L'empire.
The point is, kids...
Ce que je veux dire, c'est que les enfants
they give us a chance to be better than we are.
sont notre chance de nous amיliorer.
Better than we used to be.
D'ךtre meilleurs qu'on יtait.
You're a lot smarter than I look.
Tu es bien plus futיe que j'en ai l'air.
I'm gonna go make dessert.
Je nous prיpare un dessert.
You get the strap-on. Let's make a super baby.
Va chercher le godemichי. On va se faire un super bיbי.
Pretty sure it doesn't work that way, but we can try.
J'ai des doutes sur ta mיthode, mais essayons.
What about Krystal? But with a "K"?
Pourquoi pas Krystal avec un k ?
It's too stripper-y.
Un nom de danseuse nue.
Kevin with a "K"!
Kevin avec un k !
No, too stripper-y, too.
ַa, c'est un nom de danseur nu.
Earl!
Earl !
He's gonna go straight to jail if we name him Earl.
Il ira droit en prison si on l'appelle Earl.
What about Bruce?
Que dis-tu de Bruce ?
No.
Non.
Get down.
ְ terre.
What?
Quoi ?
Baby? Baby?
Chיrie ? Chיrie ?
I'm okay.
Je n'ai rien.
Thank God I didn't have to use the cream cheese spreader.
Dieu merci, pas eu besoin du couteau א fromage.
Please.
S'il te plaמt.
Baby, I'm so sorry.
Ma chיrie, je regrette tellement.
No!
Non !
Papa, can you hear me?
Papa, peux-tu m'entendre ?
Is it just me, or does Do You Want to Build a Snowman? from Frozen...
Suis-je le seul א trouver que Je voudrais un bonhomme de neige
sound suspiciously like Papa, Can You Hear Me? from Yentl?
ressemble יtrangement א Papa, Can You Hear Me? dans Yentl ?
Papa, can you hear me?
Papa, peux-tu m'entendre ?
And nobody fucking realizes it.
Et personne ne s'en rend compte.
Go home. You've been here for three days, okay?
Rentre chez toi. Tu es ici depuis trois jours.
You smell like somebody shit in a Civil War wound...
Tu sens comme si quelqu'un avait chiי
after it had become gangrenous.
sur une blessure gangrenיe.
They should've just amputated it. Why shit in it?
Pourquoi chier dessus au lieu d'amputer ?
Doesn't make any sense.
ַa n'a pas de sens.
I love Frozen.
J'adore La reine des neiges.
I loved her. I loved her like an ocean loves water.
Je l'aimais. Je l'aimais comme un ocיan aime l'eau.
An ocean is water.
L'ocיan, c'est de l'eau.
More importantly, I liked her. I really liked her, you know?
Plus important, elle me plaisait vraiment.
George Michael was right. I'm never gonna dance again. Fuck!
George Michael disait vrai. Je ne danserai plus jamais. Merde !
He's dead, too.
Il est mort aussi.
At least we still have Bowie.
Au moins, il nous reste Bowie.
Yeah. We still have Bowie.
Oui. Il nous reste Bowie.
I'm sorry.
Excuse-moi.
Shot after shot, it's not gonna change the fact that I think you're...
Enchaמner les verres ne changera pas le fait que je crois...
Are you pissing? Are you urinating right now?
Es-tu en train de pisser ?
You're making the face that you make when you urinate.
Tu fais cette expression quand tu pisses.
- Is he pissing? - I'm on it!
- Il pisse ? - Je m'en occupe !
There you go, Dopinder.
Bien jouי, Dopinder.
If you want to be a contract killer...
Si tu veux devenir tueur א gages,
you gotta handle a mop before you handle a gun.
tu dois manier la vadrouille avant le revolver.
Although I don't quite understand how they are at all similar.
Je ne comprends pas le lien entre eux.
Well, they both have handles. Now, leave me.
Les deux ont un manche. Laisse-moi tranquille.
Go home, Wade.
Rentre chez toi, Wade.
I don't have a home, Weas, you know. I got a...
Je n'ai plus de chez-moi, Weas, j'ai un...
Fuck! Okay, I'm fine.
Merde ! Je vais bien.
- I'm fine. - You know what "fine" stands for, Wade?
- Je vais bien. - Sais-tu ce que signifie "bien" ?
Fucked up, insecure, needy, and emotional.
Bousillי, inquiet, יmotif et nיvrosי.
According to the...
Selon le...
- Kübler-Ross. - Yeah.
- Kbler-Ross. - Oui.
According to the Kübler-Ross model...
Selon le modטle de Kbler-Ross,
denial is just one of the five stages of grief.
le dיni est l'une des cinq יtapes du deuil.
Jesus Christ, Buck!
Seigneur, Buck !
No more speaking lines for you.
Fini pour toi, le dialogue.
"I'm thinking it over!"
"J'y rיflיchis !"
Motherfuck!
Saloperie !
Fuck!
Merde !
The hell you doin' here?
Que fais-tu ici ?
Don't you know how to knock?
Tu ne sais pas frapper ?
I thought you saw me...
Je croyais que tu m'avais vu
with your ears.
avec tes oreilles.
- You're lucky I didn't shoot you in the... - The wall?
- J'aurais pu te tirer... - Dans le mur ?
The refrigerator? I'm in so much pain.
Le frigo ? J'ai si mal.
I heard the news, sweetie.
J'ai su la nouvelle.
I'm very sorry. I am.
Je suis navrיe, sincטrement.
What am I gonna do, Al?
Que vais-je faire, Al ?
Probably something terrible.
Probablement un truc terrible.
Knowing you.
Je te connais.
It was my fault.
C'יtait ma faute.
I fucking did this.
J'ai fait חa.
And all I wanna do is grab her and see her and tell her that I'm sorry, and I can't.
Je veux la voir et l'יtreindre et lui demander pardon. Impossible.
She's gone.
Elle est partie.
Sweetheart, can you speak up?
Parle plus fort, mon chou.
It's a little hard to hear you with that pity dick in your mouth.
J'ai du mal א t'entendre avec cette bite dans ta bouche.
Now, look, sugar. You need to just keep living.
ֹcoute, petit, tu dois continuer א vivre.
Thank you...
Merci,
Matthew McConaughey, your words are a treasure.
Matthew McConaughey, tes mots sont un vrai trיsor.
Listen to the pain.
ֹcoute ta douleur. Elle te raconte א la fois le passי et l'avenir.
Pain teaches us who we are, Wade.
La douleur fait de nous qui on est, Wade.
Sometimes, it's so bad, we feel like we're dying.
Parfois, on souffre tant qu'on croit mourir.
But we can't really live till we've died a little, can we?
Mais il faut mourir un peu avant de vivre.
Wade?
Wade ?
- Wade? - I'm right here, Althea.
- Wade ? - Je suis lא, Althea.
And that is the most beautiful thing I've ever heard.
C'est la plus belle chose que j'aie entendue.
You're absolutely right.
Tu as tout א fait raison.
I'm about to do something terrible.
Je vais faire un truc terrible.
There. All caught up.
Nous voilא revenus au prיsent.
You can't really live until you've died a little.
Il faut mourir un peu avant de vivre.
Let's test that theory, shall we?
Mettons la thיorie א l'essai.
Baby factory's open for business.
L'usine א bיbיs est ouverte.
Your crazy matches my crazy.
Ta folie reflטte ma folie.
I will never, ever let our child be named Todd.
Je n'accepterai pas que notre fils s'appelle Todd.
Skee-Ball token.
Un jeton de fךte foraine.
Happy International Women's Day.
Joyeuse journיe de la femme.
- Listen, I've been thinking a lot. - Really?
- J'ai rיflיchi. - ְ quoi ?
- About why we're so good together. - I love you, Wade Wilson.
- ְ pourquoi on s'entend aussi bien. - Je t'aime, Wade Wilson.
Ness?
Ness ?
Ness.
Ness.
Ness, there's something here. I can't get to you.
Il y a un problטme. Je ne peux pas te rejoindre.
Your heart's not in the right place.
Tu n'as pas le cur א la bonne place.
Wait, hold on. What?
Attends, quoi ?
Wait. What do you mean my heart's not in the right place? What does it...
Que veux-tu dire par "pas א la bonne place" ?
I'm terribly sorry for your loss, Wade.
Toutes mes condolיances, Wade.
You're broken.
Tu es un vrai dיsastre.
Oh, God. I know that voice.
Mon Dieu. Je connais cette voix.
"Heart's in the right place."
"Le cur א la bonne place."
"Heart's in the right..." What does that mean?
ַa veut dire quoi ?
You've been sleep for three days.
Tu dors depuis trois jours.
I took the liberty of dressing you.
Je me suis permis de t'habiller.
No shit.
Sans blague.
Why can't I fucking die?
Pourquoi ne puis-je pas mourir ?
Take your mask off, Wade.
Enlטve ton masque, Wade.
We must talk.
Il faut qu'on parle.
You need fresh start.
Tu dois repartir א neuf.
With training, you can be X-Man.
En t'entraמnant, tu pourrais devenir un X-Man.
You're wasting your time, Shiny Jesus. I'm not X-Man material.
Tu perds ton temps, Jיsus chromי. Je ne suis pas fait pour חa.
Understatement of the year.
Tu n'as jamais si bien dit.
Wade, Yukio. Yukio, Wade.
Wade, Yukio.
What in the fuck knuckles is this?
C'est quoi, ce bordel ?
She's my girlfriend, you intolerant shit.
Ma petite amie, sale intolיrant.
Pump the hate brakes, Fox & Friends. I'm just surprised anyone would date you.
Arrךte un peu, avec la haine.
Especially Pinkie Pie from My Little Pony.
Surtout une petite pouliche comme elle.
I like this guy.
Il me plaמt.
Give him a chance.
Laisse-lui une chance.
It's great seeing you like this.
J'aime te voir ainsi.
Yeah.
C'est חa.
Bye, Wade!
Au revoir, Wade !
Now, some ground rules while under our roof.
La maison a quelques rטgles.
"Rule number one. No killing...
"Rטgle numיro un. Dיfense de tuer
"anyone ever, no matter how bad.
"quiconque, mךme les pires mיchants.
"Rule two. Label everything in refrigerator."
"Rטgle numיro deux. Tout יtiqueter dans le frigo."
Wade?
Wade ?
Wade!
Wade !
Don't try to chase me.
Ne me cours pas aprטs.
I'm not ready to be touched again.
Je ne suis pas prךt א ךtre touchי.
All these elderly white men on the walls...
Tous ces vieux Blancs sur les murs...
Should have brought my rape whistle.
Il me faudrait mon sifflet antiviol.
Hi.
Salut.
Those were already damaged after they fell there!
Ils יtaient dיjא brisיs aprטs ךtre tombיs !
What am I supposed to do around here, anyway?
Je suis censי faire quoi ici ?
Sit in a share circle, talk about my feelings?
Parler d'יmotions en thיrapie de groupe ?
And how would I do that exactly?
Et comment ferais-je חa, au juste ?
'Cause where the fuck is everyone?
Oש sont passיs tous les autres ?
It's always just you and Negasonic Teenage Longest Name Ever...
Il n'y a que toi et l'ado au nom impossible.
Enough!
ַa suffit !
I said no touching!
Pas touche, j'ai dit !
What the fuck?
C'est quoi, ce bordel ?
You'd think the studio would throw us a bone.
Le studio aurait pu nous faire une fleur.
They can't just dust off one of the famous X-Men?
Un X-Man cיlטbre, c'יtait trop demander ?
How 'bout that putz with the giant pigeon wings?
Pourquoi pas le nul aux ailes de pigeon ?
What do those do anyway?
ְ quoi חa lui sert ?
Carry him three feet off the ground to snatch up the nearest muffin crumb?
ְ s'יlever d'un mטtre pour chiper des miettes de muffin ?
No, no, no!
Non, non !
I am not X-Man material at all.
Je ne suis pas fait pour ךtre un X-Man.
First off...
Tout d'abord...
I'm not even a virgin. Second and more...
Je ne suis pas vierge. Et...
I should have left you in the self-pitying mess I found you in.
J'aurais d te laisser t'apitoyer sur ton sort.
But this is what friends do. They show up!
Mais les amis sont lא l'un pour l'autre !
Not when convenient or easy.
Pas juste quand c'est facile.
When hard, and you always make it hard.
Quand c'est dur aussi. Avec toi, c'est toujours dur.
You are unwell.
Tu ne vas pas bien.
I'm sticking my neck out bringing you here.
Je cours un risque en t'emmenant ici.
Wait. One of the assholes who killed Vanessa got away.
Attends. Un des enfoirיs qui ont tuי Vanessa a fui.
Jesus Christ!
Seigneur !
Wade, whoever they are...
Wade, qui qu'ils soient,
we track them down and bring them to justice.
on les retrouvera et on les traduira en justice.
It was me.
C'יtait moi.
I'm the asshole who got away.
Je suis l'enfoirי qui a fui.
I killed every last one of them, except me.
Je les ai tous tuיs, sauf moi.
Couldn't kill me.
Je n'ai pas pu me tuer.
We were gonna start a family.
On allait fonder une famille.
We were gonna be a family.
On allait devenir une famille.
Wade...
Wade...
Vanessa is gone. She's not coming back.
Vanessa nous a quittיs. Elle ne reviendra pas.
This may not be family you want...
Ceci n'est pas la famille que tu voudrais,
but it's family you need.
mais c'est la famille qu'il te faut.
You have a good heart. It belongs here where it can grow.
Tu as un grand cur. Ici, il pourra s'יpanouir.
What did you say?
Qu'as-tu dit ?
About my heart?
ְ propos de mon cur ?
I think I'm in the right place.
Je crois que je suis א la bonne place.
Wade.
Wade.
Wade!
Wade !
Hey, I was just taking Cerebro for a spin here...
Je faisais juste un petit tour avec Cerebro
looking deep into the future.
pour voir l'avenir lointain.
This thing...
Ce machin...
- That's not how Cerebro works.
- ַa ne fonctionne... - ... pas ainsi.
Yes. Yes, it is.
Mais oui.
- We have mission.
- On a... - ... une mission.
We do. You do.
Oui. Du moins, toi.
You guys be safe out there.
Soyez prudents lא-bas.
- No, I want you to join. - No, you want me to join.
- Joins-toi א nous. - Tu veux que je me...
I'm sorry, what?
Pardon, quoi ?
You are ready.
Tu es prךt.
That's a terrible idea, and it's gonna end badly.
C'est une mauvaise idיe et חa finira mal.
You wanna know how I know? I'll give you a hint.
Comment je le sais ? Un indice.
It's on my head and smells like Patrick Stewart.
C'est sur ma tךte et חa sent Patrick Stewart.
Be at the X-Jet in five.
Sois au X-Jet dans cinq minutes.
Irene Merryweather, WHIT News.
Irene Merryweather des actualitיs WHIT.
Live here at a breaking news situation
Je suis sur le site d'un incident au foyer Essex de rיadaptation des mutants.
A mutant boy is appearing to have some sort of an incident...
Un garחon mutant semble en crise.
- with police here behind me. - Get away from me!
- La police est ici. - ֹloignez-vous !
There are two police vehicles that are overturned.
Deux autopatrouilles ont יtי renversיes.
- There are open fires. - Fuck off! Stay back!
- Il y a des incendies. - Dיgagez !
- A scene of absolute chaos here. - Calm down.
- C'est le chaos. - Du calme.
I'll burn you! You stay back!
Je vous brlerai !
Get away from me!
N'avancez pas ! ֹloignez-vous !
You wanna fucking die?
Voulez-vous mourir ?
And it appears as if the X-Men are arriving...
On dirait que les X-Men arrivent...
Scatter!
ֹcartez-vous !
...with what appears to be a trainee.
... avec une recrue.
Everyone, calm down! The pros are here. I...
Calmez-vous ! Les pros sont ici !
We're the X-Men!
On est les X-Men !
A dated metaphor for racism in the '60s.
Mיtaphore dיsuטte du racisme des annיes 60.
So, respect.
Respect א vous.
At ease, Officer.
Repos, monsieur l'agent.
What are you doing?
Qu'est-ce que tu fais ?
My job!
Mon travail !
You're the one who said I was ready, and I frankly disagreed with you.
Tu as dit que j'יtais prךt. Je n'יtais pas d'accord.
But here we are, trying to overcome our differences.
Mais on met nos diffיrends derriטre nous.
Like Beyoncé says, "Please...
Comme Beyoncי l'a dit : "Je t'en prie,
- "Please, stop cheating on me." - Hey!
- "arrךte de me tromper." - Hי !
This is the fifth incident.
C'est le cinquiטme incident.
This kid needs to be in the Ice Box, not here.
Le petit doit aller au Frigo.
Russell belongs in our care.
La place de Russell est ici.
Not in prison. I assure you...
Pas en prison. Je vous assure
- we have everything under control. - Stay back! I'll burn you!
- qu'on gטre la situation. - Reculez ! Je vous brlerai !
Not getting a real "under control" vibe here, Marty.
Je n'ai pas vraiment l'impression que vous gיrez, Marty.
- It is Glen, isn't it? - Daniel.
- Glen, c'est חa ? - Daniel.
I'll ask the questions. Let me talk to the kid.
Je pose les questions. Je parlerai au garחon.
You stay here with your weird, secret sex lips.
Restez lא avec vos drפles de lטvres sensuelles.
You wanna die?
Voulez-vous mourir ?
This kid's adorable. I don't know why I packed the hollow points.
Il est adorable. Que fais-je avec mes balles א pointe creuse ?
I'll burn your balls off!
Je te brlerai les couilles !
First day. I'm so nervous!
Premiטre journיe. Je suis si nerveux !
Did you just say "hollow points"?
Des balles א pointe creuse ?
Yeah, probably should've brought a Super Soaker.
Oui, il m'aurait plutפt fallu un fusil א l'eau.
Hi, there!
Salut !
Stay back or Justin Bieber dies!
Reculez, sinon Justin Bieber va mourir.
Justin Bieber. He called you Justin Bieber.
Il t'a traitיe de Justin Bieber.
Hold on! Wait, wait, wait!
Attends !
Okay, let's not do whatever that is.
Ne fais pas חa, peu importe ce que c'est.
Okay? Let's just talk!
D'accord ? On va discuter.
It's Russell, right?
Russell, c'est חa ?
- Firefist.
- Firefist.
That's a great name. Where does it burn?
Chouette nom. Oש חa brle ?
Just the fist, or all the way up to the elbow?
Juste le poing ou jusqu'au coude ?
Definitely all the way up to the elbow.
Jusqu'au coude, c'est יvident.
Come quietly, or there will be trouble.
Viens, sinon tu auras des ennuis.
- You stole that from Robocop! - That's from Robocop!
- Tu as pris חa de Robocop ! - C'est Robocop !
Just stand down! You're embarrassing me. Look, Fire...
ֹloigne-toi ! Tu me gךnes. ֹcoute, Fire...
Oh, my God! I can't say it! I'm so sorry!
Mon Dieu ! Pardon, je n'arrive pas א le dire !
Oh, shit! That fucking does it!
Oh, merde ! ַa suffit !
Put your hands behind your knees and get down on your head! Now!
Les mains derriטre les genoux, la tךte א terre, vite !
Wade! What was first rule?
Wade ! La premiטre rטgle, c'est quoi ?
Label everything in the refrigerator!
Tout יtiqueter dans le frigo !
- Do not escalate! - Rules are meant to be broken!
- Ne rien empirer ! - Les rטgles, חa s'enfreint !
That's the exact opposite of what they're meant for!
Au contraire, il faut les respecter !
Fuck! Fine!
Merde ! Trטs bien !
I'll start from the beginning.
Reprenons du dיbut.
My name is Deadpool, and I'm an X-Man.
Je m'appelle Deadpool et je suis un X-Man.
- Trainee! - Shut it!
- En formation ! - La ferme !
Look, I get it.
ֹcoute, je comprends.
All right, you're scared.
Tu as peur.
Alone.
Tu es seul.
You got no family. I didn't have a family, either.
Tu n'as pas de famille. Je n'en avais pas non plus.
You live in this dump. Guess what? I used to live in a shithole just like it.
Tu vis dans ce trou. Devine quoi. J'ai vיcu dans un trou moi aussi.
But you know something? To make matters worse...
Mais tu sais quoi ? Pour empirer les choses,
it's a confusing time in your life right now.
tu es א une dure יtape de la vie.
Your body is going through some fiery changes.
Ton corps subit des changements fulgurants.
Too far? I went too far, didn't I?
Trop loin ? Je suis allי trop loin ?
That was effervescent.
C'יtait effervescent.
Stay in school, kid.
Reste aux יtudes, petit.
Or don't. I didn't.
Ou pas. Moi, j'ai dיcrochי.
And I'm an X-Man.
Et je suis un X-Man.
Trainee.
En formation.
Fuck it!
Au diable tout חa !
Superhero landing coming up!
Atterrissage de superhיros !
Fuck, fuck, fuck!
Merde !
That is so not practical.
Ce n'est pas pratique.
I could get used to this X-Man shit.
Je prends got א la vie de X-Man.
- Trainee!
- En formation !
Get a power restraint on him. Now!
Neutralisez-le !
Calm down, squirt. It's over. We got ya.
Calme-toi, petit. C'est fini. On est lא.
What's that do?
ְ quoi חa sert ?
Power-dampening collar. Shuts down all mutant abilities.
ַa annule les pouvoirs. ַa neutralise les mutants.
You can't get it off. Unless you've got a grenade.
ַa ne s'enlטve pas א moins d'avoir une grenade.
Could've used one of those in the first act.
Il m'aurait fallu חa dans le premier acte.
Thank you!
Merci !
That was absolutely thrilling.
C'יtait enlevant.
True heroism in action.
De l'hיroןsme א l'יtat pur.
We are in your debt.
Nous avons une dette envers vous.
We can take it from here.
On s'occupe de la suite.
Take me to the Ice Box, please!
Emmenez-moi au Frigo, je vous en prie !
Anywhere's better than here.
N'importe oש sauf ici.
Believe me, son, you do not wanna go to the Ice Box.
Crois-moi, tu ne veux pas y aller.
Let's get you inside, young man.
On va rentrer, mon garחon.
No, wait, wait. Wait.
Non, attendez.
You guys stay there.
N'approchez pas.
Those guys hurt you?
T'ont-ils fait mal ?
Who?
Qui ?
Baldilocks? Jared Kushner?
Le chauve ? Jared Kushner ?
Both of 'em?
Les deux ?
Fuck it.
Au diable tout חa.
Four or five moments!
Quatre ou cinq moments !
I'm sorry?
Pardon ?
That's all it takes to be a hero.
C'est tout ce qu'il faut pour ךtre un hיros.
People think you wake up a hero...
Les gens croient qu'on se rיveille en hיros,
brush your teeth a hero...
qu'on se brosse les dents en hיros,
ejaculate into a soap dispenser a hero.
qu'on יjacule dans le porte-savon en hיros.
But, no, being a hero takes only a few moments!
Mais ךtre un hיros ne prend que quelques moments !
A few moments...
Quelques moments
doing the ugly stuff no one else will do.
pour faire les choses que les autres refusent.
No!
Non !
Stand down! Hold your fire!
Ne tirez pas !
- Wade, what did you do? - Colossus, no!
- Wade, qu'as-tu fait ? - Colossus, non !
That kid was abused!
Il est maltraitי ! ַa se voit.
- You can tell. You can always tell! - We have rules!
- C'est יvident ! - On a des rטgles !
You are not judge, jury or executioner!
Tu n'es ni juge, ni jurי, ni bourreau !
Fuck your rules! I fight for what's right!
Au diable tes rטgles ! Je me bats pour la justice !
And sometimes you gotta fight dirty!
ַa requiert parfois des coups bas !
You let me down for the last time, Wade.
Tu m'as laissי tombי pour la derniטre fois, Wade.
Okay, get these guys in the pod.
Mettez-les dans le camion,
Take them to the Ice Box.
direction le Frigo.
Hey, baby!
Salut, mon beau !
I wonder what gang I'll be in.
Je me demande dans quel gang je serai.
Yeah!
Ouais !
Is there, like, a Sorting Hat? Hi.
Y a-t-il un choixpeau magique ? Salut.
Go!
Avance !
Hard left, douchebag.
ְ gauche, enfoirי.
Please, after you.
Aprטs toi.
Another disgusting mutant off the streets. God bless America.
Un mutant rיpugnant de moins dans les rues. Merci, mon Dieu.
Let's get a taco.
Allons manger un taco.
Nighty-night, you annoying prick!
Bonne nuit, pauvre con !
I'mma tell you what the big lie is.
Je vais te dire le gros mensonge.
Toilet paper.
Le papier de toilette.
Toilet paper is a plenty fine appetizer.
Ce n'est pas mal comme entrיe en matiטre.
But, then...
Mais ensuite,
Huggies Natural Care wet wipes.
les lingettes Huggies Natural Care.
That's your main course.
C'est le plat principal.
They're soft, they're moist. They're for babies.
Elles sont douces et humides. C'est pour les bיbיs.
Finally, one more pass with the toilet paper,
Enfin, un dernier coup de papier de toilette pour enlever
maybe clear out that excess moisture.
l'excטs d'humiditי.
Maybe treat yourself to a blow and go, if you can get you a hair dryer.
Peut-ךtre un peu d'air chaud si tu as un sיchoir.
Just about 30 seconds will do you good.
Juste une trentaine de secondes.
The fuck?
C'est quoi, ce bordel ?
Year?
L'annיe ?
What?
Quoi ?
What year is it?
En quelle annיe on est ?
What kind of dumbass question is that to ask?
Quelle question stupide !
You're a long way from your superpowers.
Tu es loin de tes superpouvoirs.
Yeah.
Oui.
Fuck!
Merde !
I wanted to be a superhero.
Je voulais ךtre un superhיros.
Always wanted a real super suit.
J'ai toujours voulu une combinaison.
What happened?
Que s'est-il passי ?
When was the last time you saw a plus-sized superhero?
As-tu dיjא vu un superhיros dodu ?
Never.
Jamais.
The industry discriminates.
Le milieu discrimine contre nous.
Fuck superheroes.
Au diable les superhיros.
Fuck everyone.
Au diable tout le monde.
The first thing I wanna do when I get out of here...
La premiטre chose que je ferai en sortant d'ici,
burn the headmaster alive...
c'est brler le directeur vif
and then take a selfie with his smoldering corpse.
et me prendre en photo avec son cadavre fumant.
Who says prison isn't reformative?
On dit que la prison, חa rיhabilite.
Fucker hates mutants.
Il dיteste les mutants.
Blessed are the wicked who are healed by my hand.
Bיnis sont les dיviants qui sont guיris par ma main.
Your abilities.
Vos pouvoirs.
I know how seductive they are.
Je sais qu'ils sont sיduisants.
Now, please don't cry.
Ne pleure pas.
Tomorrow, we'll find the biggest guy in here...
Demain, on trouvera le plus gros type ici
and we'll make him our...
et on en fera notre...
What was that?
C'יtait quoi, חa ?
That is the biggest guy in here.
Le plus gros type ici.
Fun fact about the Ice Box...
Bon א savoir sur le Frigo :
though no one's ever seen it, they keep a monster in the basement.
personne ne l'a jamais vu, mais il y a un monstre au sous-sol.
Right next to a huge, steaming bowl of foreshadowing.
Juste א cפtי d'un gros bol tout chaud de prיfiguration.
Look.
ֹcoute.
I can't protect you.
Je ne peux pas te protיger.
With this collar on, my superpower is just unbridled cancer.
Avec ce collier, mon superpouvoir est un cancer non circonscrit.
Give me a bow and arrow, I'm basically Hawkeye.
Avec un arc et des flטches, je serais il de Faucon.
Now, if you'll excuse me...
Si tu veux bien m'excuser...
I've got tumors to grow. Vanessa awaits.
Je dois faire grossir mes tumeurs. Vanessa m'attend.
I'll start by making us a shank.
Je vais nous fabriquer un poignard.
- Good listening. - I stole that guard's pen...
- Bien יcoutי. - J'ai volי un stylo
and stashed it in the old prison wallet, if you know what I'm saying.
et l'ai mis dans mon portefeuille de prison, si tu me comprends.
Prison wallet?
Ton portefeuille de prison ?
I really hope I don't know what you're saying.
J'espטre vraiment ne rien comprendre.
I can hear you rummaging around in there.
Je t'entends fouiller lא-dedans.
And to update you on the story reported earlier...
Mise א jour sur l'histoire rapportיe plus tפt :
after a lengthy standoff
aprטs une longue confrontation devant
two mutants were arrested and transported to the Ice Box...
deux mutants ont יtי arrךtיs et conduits au Frigo...
Entering repair mode.
Rיparation.
...several police cars were destroyed and the X-Men were called in to restore order.
... autopatrouilles ont יtי dיtruites, et les X-Men ont יtי appelיs en renfort.
Cells seven and nine now off-limits for medical personnel.
Cellules sept et neuf fermיes au personnel mיdical.
Don't do that.
Ne fais pas חa.
What? Why are you winking at me?
Pourquoi me fais-tu des clins d'il ?
I got your back.
Je veille sur toi.
Oh, my God.
Oh, Seigneur.
You're sick, I gotta protect you.
Tu es malade. Je te protטge.
Just leave me alone, kid.
Laisse-moi tranquille.
Oh, great.
Oh, gיnial.
Well, hello there, new fish.
Salut, le nouveau.
It's nice to see some fresh faces around here.
C'est bien de voir de nouveaux visages.
I've done some light catalog work...
J'ai posי dans des catalogues,
but, really, modeling is just a stepping stone to acting.
mais en fait, je rךve d'ךtre acteur.
I was talking to him.
C'est א lui que je parlais.
Have we met? I can't place your mustache.
On se connaמt ? Ta moustache ne me dit rien.
- Black Tom Cassidy. - White Wade Wilson.
- Tom le Noir Cassidy. - Wade le Blanc Wilson.
What's your superpower? Cultural appropriation?
C'est quoi, ton pouvoir ? L'appropriation culturelle ?
You're supposed to be the toughest cunt in here.
Tu es censי ךtre le pire dur א cuire ici.
You don't look like much to me.
Tu n'as l'air de rien.
First rule of the yard, fuckface...
Premiטre rטgle de la prison, tךte de nud.
find the biggest guy and make him your...
Trouver le plus gros type et en faire...
Second biggest guy.
Le deuxiטme plus gros.
The last thing I need is more hepatitis.
Je n'ai pas besoin d'une autre hיpatite.
It's slippery, too. This table needs a wipe down!
C'est glissant. Il faut essuyer la table !
Can we get a wipe down on the table?
Peut-on essuyer la table ?
Kid, I think you picked the wrong side.
Tu as choisi le mauvais camp.
No, I didn't! He's my friend!
Non ! C'est mon ami !
Zip it. We're not friends.
La ferme. On n'est pas amis.
You're about to get dick-slapped.
Ta bite va y passer.
I had so much fun! You were like...
Je me suis יclatי ! Tu faisais...
And I was like, "Take a seat, shit dick."
Et je disais : "Dיgage, grosse merde."
Just let me die in peace.
Laisse-moi mourir en paix.
We make a great team!
On forme une super יquipe !
Oh, God! We're not a team.
Mon Dieu ! On n'est pas une יquipe.
Why'd you say that back there? We're friends, partners.
Pourquoi dis-tu חa ? On est amis, partenaires.
We're not partners or friends.
On n'est ni amis ni partenaires.
This doesn't end with us riding into the sunset.
On ne partira pas vers le soleil couchant.
It ends with me dying of cancer...
Je vais mourir du cancer,
and you winning the Ice Box award for softest mouth.
et tu vas gagner le prix de la bouche la plus douce.
There's only one person in this world that I care about, and she's gone.
La seule personne au monde dont je me soucie est partie.
You wanna survive?
Tu veux survivre ?
Stop trying to shank the biggest guys in here...
N'essaie pas de poignarder les plus gros types ici
and make friends with them.
et deviens plutפt leur ami.
Make friends with someone.
Deviens l'ami de quelqu'un.
Anyone but me.
De n'importe qui sauf moi.
Maybe even Black Tim.
Peut-ךtre mךme de Tim le Noir.
Black Evan, I don't know.
Evan le Noir. Je ne sais pas.
All I remember is he was African-American.
Je me souviens seulement qu'il יtait noir.
System malfunctioning. Cells 7, 12, 14, 27.
Dיfaillance du systטme. Cellules 7, 12, 14, 27.
Back in your cells, you filthy mutants! Get in there!
Dans vos cellules, sales mutants ! Allez-y !
Cells 1, 3, 7, 8.
Cellules 1, 3, 7, 8.
Searching.
Recherche.
Cell 04 located.
Cellule 4 repיrיe.
Door won't open!
La porte ne s'ouvre pas !
On your fucking knees!
ְ genoux !
That was our cell.
C'יtait notre cellule.
What did I do to piss off a grumpy old fucker with a Winter Soldier arm?
Qu'ai-je fait pour enrager un vieux grincheux
Get away from me, kid!
ֹloigne-toi de moi, petit !
Listen to me! Go!
ֹcoute-moi ! Sauve-toi !
Hello, Russell.
Salut, Russell.
Hello, superpowers.
Bonjour, les superpouvoirs.
Who are you?
Qui es-tu ?
I'm Batman.
Batman.
That's got some zip.
C'est puissant.
Don't feel bad. Even I can't kill me.
Ne te sens pas mal. Mךme moi, je ne peux pas me tuer.
Talk!
Parle !
What kind of spineless shit stick tries to kill a 14-year-old boy?
Quel genre de salaud veut tuer un garחon de 14 ans ?
You might wanna start talking!
Tu devrais rיpondre !
'Cause I got a long history of firing at times like this!
J'ai tendance א tirer dans les moments comme חa.
The name's Cable.
Je m'appelle Cable.
I'm from the future. Just walk away.
Je viens de l'avenir. ֹloigne-toi.
So, you're from the future.
Tu viens de l'avenir.
I have three questions then.
J'ai trois questions pour toi.
One, is dubstep still a thing?
Un, le dubstep existe encore ?
Two, which Sharknado are we on?
Deux, combien de volets compte la saga Sharknado ?
And three, at what point do audiences say...
Et trois, quand le public en aura-t-il assez
"Enough with the robotic arms"?
des bras bioniques ?
Dubstep's for pussies.
Le dubstep, c'est pour les lגches.
You're so dark!
Tu es lugubre !
Are you sure you're not from the DC universe?
Tu ne viendrais pas d'une bיdי DC ?
I love dubstep!
J'adore le dubstep !
Is that a fanny pack?
Un sac banane ?
I used to have one of those in 1990-never.
J'en avais un en 1990... Ah non, jamais.
Something to remember you by.
Un petit souvenir.
Give me that back! That goes with me everywhere.
Redonne-moi חa ! Je l'emporte partout.
Like the memory of your fucking fanny pack!
Comme le souvenir de ton foutu sac banane !
Why are you protecting the kid?
Pourquoi protטges-tu le petit ?
I don't give a fuck about him...
Je me fiche de lui et du fait
and his Are You My Mother? complex!
qu'il me prenne pour sa mטre !
What's this one do?
ַa, חa fait quoi ?
In every film, there's a moment when the hero hits rock bottom.
Chaque film comporte un moment oש le hיros touche le fond du baril.
In Cool Runnings, it was when John Candy's prized bobsled broke.
Dans Les apprentis champions, c'est quand John Candy se fait briser son bobsleigh.
In Human Centipede, it was when those people...
Dans Human Centipede, c'est quand ces gens
signed on to be in that movie.
ont acceptי de jouer dans le film.
But in this film, well...
Mais dans ce film-ci, bien...
you're looking at it.
On y est.
On your fucking knees, mutant.
ְ genoux, foutu mutant.
Rock...
Baril,
meet bottom.
voici ton fond.
I love you, Wade Wilson.
Je t'aime, Wade Wilson.
Ness?
Ness ?
Hey, Ness!
Hי, Ness !
Ness, can you let me in?
Ness, peux-tu me laisser entrer ?
Please! Please.
Je t'en prie !
Jesus.
Seigneur.
You're not giving me a lot of direction here.
Tu ne m'aides pas beaucoup.
I'm at the end of my rope.
Je suis au bout du rouleau.
Then I joined the X-Men.
Je me suis joint aux X-Men.
I went to prison.
Je suis allי en prison.
Is it the kid?
C'est le petit ?
Kids give us a chance to be better than we used to be.
Les enfants nous donnent la chance de nous amיliorer.
The kid!
Le petit !
That's exactly what she meant. Your heart needs to be in the right place.
Voilא ce qu'elle voulait dire. Le cur א la bonne place.
I'm not gonna abandon this kid.
Je n'abandonnerai pas le petit.
He's never had anyone, ever.
Personne n'a jamais יtי lא pour lui.
I need to be selfless.
Je dois ךtre altruiste.
Yeah, but what does that mean?
Mais qu'est-ce que חa veut dire ?
It means I'm gonna save Russell.
Je vais sauver Russell.
Maybe I couldn't save Vanessa...
Je n'ai pas sauvי Vanessa,
but maybe I can save a robust teenager from New Zealand.
mais je sauverai un ado dodu de Nouvelle-Zיlande.
Yeah, but what I mean is, like, the word "selfless."
Je parlais du mot altruiste.
I literally don't know what that means.
J'ignore ce qu'il veut dire.
Jesus Christ.
Bon sang.
Okay, look. According to my guy, okay...
ֹcoute, selon mon contact,
those muties are being transferred to a supermax, 80 miles away.
les mutants se font transfיrer en sיcuritי ultramaximale, א 130 km.
Great, I'll pick 'em off along the way.
Super. Je le cueillerai en route.
Hold your testicles there, buddy, okay? We're talking about an armored convoy...
Relaxe tes couilles, mon vieux. On parle d'un convoi blindי
and a vicious super soldier from the future...
et d'un super soldat enragי de l'avenir
that is looking to turn your skull into a fuckable ashtray.
qui veut transformer ton crגne en cendrier.
You know what we need to do? We need to build a fucking team.
Sais-tu ce qu'il nous faut ? On va assembler une יquipe.
We need 'em tough, morally flexible...
Une יquipe de durs א la moralitי douteuse
and young enough so they can carry this franchise 10 to 12 years.
assez jeune pour porter cette saga durant dix א douze ans.
My body is an instrument of death.
Mon corps est une machine א tuer.
Not now, Dopinder.
Pas maintenant, Dopinder.
I could be of great use.
Je pourrais ךtre trטs utile.
What's your superpower?
Quel est ton superpouvoir ?
- Courage. - That's adorable.
- Le courage. - C'est adorable.
Do you have the courage to check and see...
Aurais-tu le courage de vיrifier
if there are enough sanitary napkins in the dispenser?
le distributeur de serviettes sanitaires ?
Yes, sir.
Oui, monsieur.
I'm sorry you had to see that, although I'm glad you heard it.
Navrי que tu aies vu חa, mais content que tu l'aies entendu.
All right, I'll put out a call for resumes.
Je lance un appel de candidatures.
But we're not paying medical or dental.
Mais on n'offre pas d'assurance mיdicale.
It's time to get back on LinkedIn.
Retournons sur LinkedIn.
Transport will begin at 0800 hours...
Dיpart א 8 h...
Oi.
Hי !
What the fuck do you want?
Qu'est-ce que tu veux ?
That's my fucking pudding.
C'est mon foutu dessert.
- Fuck your pudding! - You like pudding?
- Au diable ton dessert ! - Tu aimes ?
Hello?
Hי-ho !
I know you're in there.
Je sais que tu es lא.
Must be hard being the biggest guy in here.
ַa doit ךtre dur d'ךtre le plus gros type ici.
Lonely at the top, eh?
On se sent seul au sommet, non ?
They're moving us tomorrow.
On va dיmיnager demain.
Maybe I can get you out of here.
J'arriverai peut-ךtre א te libיrer.
And we can make the whole world our bitch.
On fera du monde entier notre petite pute.
We need a secret code.
Il nous faut un code secret.
No, that's stupid, Russell. Idiot.
Non, Russell, c'est ridicule.
We're a team. We're like thugs, we're like gangsters.
On forme une יquipe. On est des voyous, des gangsters.
I'm like Tupac, and you're like Ice Cube.
Je suis Tupac, et toi, Ice Cube.
Supposedly, she can rap, too.
Il paraמt qu'elle sait rapper.
I like that. Terrific, these are all terrific.
Oui. ַa me plaמt. C'est gיnial, tout חa.
Meet Bedlam.
Voici Bedlam.
Cool name! Superpowers?
Chouette nom ! Tes superpouvoirs ?
I can distort electrical fields.
Je sais dיformer les champs יlectriques.
Including the one inside your brain...
Y compris celui de votre cerveau,
causing anxiety, confusion...
crיant de l'anxiיtי, de la confusion,
pain.
de la douleur.
So, basically, you're Dave Matthews.
En gros, tu es Dave Matthews.
We can use him.
Il nous sera utile.
I'm Zeitgeist.
Je m'appelle Zeitgeist.
Cool. I like it.
Gיnial. J'aime חa.
So you have the power to put your finger on the pulse of society?
Tu as donc le pouvoir de cerner l'air du temps ?
No.
Non.
No, I spit acidic vomit.
Je crache du vomi acide.
- Do you want me to demonstrate? - No!
- Je vous fais une dיmonstration ? - Non !
- We'll take your word for it. - Thank you. Yeah.
- On te croit. - Merci.
Listen, we've all eaten at Arby's, okay?
On a tous dיjא mangי chez Arby's.
And this is the Vanisher.
Voici Fantפme.
But...
Mais...
Vanisher!
Fantפme !
- Nice! - Right?
- Chouette ! - Pas vrai ?
He's not here, is he?
Il n'est pas lא, hein ?
He may be running late.
Il a peut-ךtre du retard.
My name's Rusty, but I go by Shatterstar.
Je m'appelle Rusty, alias Shatterstar.
That's good, yeah.
C'est bien.
- "Rusty" is terrible. - Toughie.
- "Rusty", c'est moche. - Dur coup.
- So, where are you from? - The planet Mojo World.
- D'oש viens-tu ? - De la planטte Mojoverse.
- So you're an alien, I guess. - Bad name.
- Tu es un extraterrestre. - Nom moche.
How does that help us?
En quoi חa nous serait utile ?
I'm basically better than you at everything.
Je suis meilleur que vous dans tout.
Just once, I'm gonna find a planet of people
Un jour, je trouverai une planטte de gens pires que moi dans tout.
A whole bunch of functional idiots.
Une bande d'imbיciles fonctionnels.
I'm gonna go there, and I'm gonna be their Superman.
J'irai lא et je serai leur Superman.
Isn't that Canada?
Tu parles du Canada ?
You shut your goddamn trash mouth!
Arrךte de dire des conneries !
- Meet... - Domino.
- Voici... - Domino.
- What's your shtick? - I'm lucky.
- Tu fais quoi ? - Je suis chanceuse.
If you're so lucky, then what are you doing here with us?
Que fais-tu ici, dans ce cas ?
I don't know yet.
Je ne le sais pas encore.
What's that supposed to mean?
Que veux-tu dire ?
It means that I don't know yet.
Que je ne le sais pas encore.
But there's a reason why I'm here, and I'll know when I know.
Je suis ici pour une raison. Je le saurai quand je le saurai.
Everything usually works out for me.
Tout s'arrange pour moi.
Luck isn't a superpower.
La chance n'est pas un superpouvoir.
- Yes, it is. - No, it isn't.
- Mais oui. - Mais non.
- No, ma'am.
- Non, madame.
Mario No-pez.
Du tout.
- Yeah. - Nacho cheese.
- Oui. - Oh, que non.
- No, it definitely is. I really... - There's no way that it...
- Ce l'est vraiment. - Jamais de la vie.
- Sorry, I was interrupting you. - Sorry. No, I interrupted you.
- Pardon, je t'ai interrompu. - Non, c'est moi.
No, no, no. You can go first.
Vas-y d'abord.
I was just gonna say, "No, it isn't."
J'allais dire : "Pas du tout."
I was gonna just bring it back to that yes, it is.
Et moi : "Tout א fait."
Let's meet in the middle and say, "No, it isn't."
Faisons un compromis et avouons que non.
- But it is. - Okay.
- Mais ce l'est. - D'accord.
- You're hired! - You're hired.
- On t'embauche ! - On t'embauche.
Oh, lucky me.
Oh, quelle chance !
She's great.
Elle est super.
And last, but not least...
Le dernier, mais non le moindre...
Peter.
Peter.
Am I getting catfished here or...?
C'est une arnaque ou...
- Any powers you wanna tell us about? - No.
- As-tu des pouvoirs א nous dיcrire ? - Non.
I don't have one.
Je n'en ai aucun.
I just saw the ad and thought it looked fun.
J'ai vu l'annonce, et חa avait l'air chouette.
You're in.
On t'embauche.
- Yeah. - Fuck!
- Oui. - Merde !
Let's go!
On y va !
This is Convoy 17 departing the Ice Box.
Ici le convoi 17. On quitte le Frigo.
We are en route.
On est en route.
Peacetime makes people soft.
La paix crיe des mauviettes.
I was born into war.
Je suis nי en temps de guerre.
Bred into it.
J'ai יtי יlevי pour חa.
- Okay. - People think they understand pain.
- D'accord. - Les gens croient comprendre la douleur.
What's the most pain you've ever felt?
Quelle est la pire que tu aies ressentie ?
- These restraints are pretty... - I've got a list.
- Ces attaches sont... - J'ai une liste.
We're gonna work down it.
On va la suivre.
Together.
Ensemble.
Number one, I'm gonna bend something.
Je vais d'abord plier un truc.
Something that was not meant to bend.
Un truc qui n'est pas fait pour ךtre pliי.
I'm gonna stop you right there because I'm not gonna make it to two.
Arrךtons חa lא. Je ne me rendrai pas au point deux.
I won't even make it to one.
Je n'endurerai mךme pas le un.
I don't do well with pain, you know.
La douleur, non merci.
If I stub my toe, I'm done for the day.
Si je me cogne l'orteil, ma journיe est fichue.
I cried when they canceled Felicity.
J'ai pleurי quand Felicity a יtי annulי.
When I get really scared, I get nervous erections. I have one right now.
La peur me fait bander. Comme en ce moment.
Don't look. It'll only make it worse.
Ne regarde pas. Ce sera pire.
I don't want you to hurt me, and I'll tell you anything you wanna know.
Ne me torture pas. Je te dirai tout ce que tu veux savoir.
Except for where they are.
Sauf leur emplacement.
Russell's in a convoy heading southbound on Gerry Duggan Parkway.
Russell est dans un convoi direction sud sur l'autoroute Gerry Duggan.
The monster's with them. I wouldn't fuck with him.
Le monstre est avec eux. Je me tiendrais loin.
You all know the plan.
Vous connaissez le plan.
Intercept the convoy, grab the boy. But not inappropriately!
Intercepter le convoi, s'emparer du petit. Sans attouchements !
You know what, I wouldn't fuck with Deadpool either.
Tu sais, j'יviterais Deadpool aussi.
Because he's built a team. He's unstoppable.
Il a une יquipe. On peut pas l'arrךter.
He has an ass pen. He'll stab you with it.
Il a un stylo dans le cul. Il vous poignardera.
Watch out for this guy, Cable!
Attention א ce type, Cable !
He's very short, 5'11". Not like in the comics.
Il est petit, environ 1,80 m. Pas comme dans la bיdי.
And if we succeed, we all go home early.
Si on rיussit, on sera vite rentrיs.
there's a wind advisory in effect.
qu'il va venter fort.
A little turbulent up here.
Il y a des turbulences.
I don't know much about this Cable fella...
Je ne sais pas grand-chose de Cable,
but I guarantee he hasn't killed as many people as melanoma has.
mais il a srement tuי moins de gens que le mיlanome.
We're getting close!
On approche !
As a former X-Man...
En tant qu'ancien X-Man...
- Trainee. - Thank you, Bedlam.
- En formation. - Merci, Bedlam.
I was always appalled by the blatant sexism in the group's name.
J'ai toujours יtי rיpugnי par le sexisme du nom du groupe.
X-Men! Men!
Les X-Men ! Des hommes !
The point is, our group will be forward thinking.
Notre groupe sera plus progressiste.
Gender neutral.
Il inclura tous les genres.
From now on, we'll be known as...
On nous appellera...
X-Force.
X-Force.
Isn't that a little derivative?
Tu manquais d'inspiration ?
I don't recall asking your opinion, Peter!
Je ne t'ai pas demandי ton opinion, Peter !
That wasn't me.
Je n'ai rien dit.
Hang the laundry out at 1,300 feet...
On va sauter en parachute א 400 mטtres,
intercept the convoy, and grab the boy.
intercepter le convoi et sauver le petit.
Let's bring on the carnage, baby!
C'est l'heure du carnage !
Get me on the ground, watch me go!
On se dיchaמnera une fois א terre !
Yeah!
Oui !
I can't wait to kill!
J'ai hגte de tuer !
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Hי ! Hי !
I just wanna say how proud I am of this team.
Je suis trטs fier de cette יquipe.
You know, you guys look amazing!
Vous ךtes splendides !
Vanisher, I have no doubt you look amazing too.
Fantפme, tu es srement splendide aussi.
This is the family that I've always dreamed of having and I...
Vous ךtes la famille que je rךvais d'avoir.
Shit.
Merde.
I just get a little choked up sometimes.
Il m'arrive d'ךtre יmu.
I hate to interrupt, but is anybody nervous about the high winds?
ַa ne vous rend pas nerveux, ces vents violents ?
- Gary. - My name's Peter.
- Gary. - Peter.
I realize that you're new to this, but relax.
C'est nouveau pour toi, mais dיtends-toi.
You've been chosen by a higher power.
Tu as יtי choisi par un ךtre supיrieur.
- Did he just call himself God? - I think he did.
- Il se compare א Dieu ? - Je crois que oui.
- I'd like to go home. - And I'd like...
- J'aimerais rentrer. - J'aimerais
the McRib to be available year round, but sometimes dreams don't come true.
que le McRib soit offert toute l'annיe, mais on peut toujours rךver.
I spent 10 years in Special Forces.
J'ai passי dix ans dans les Forces spיciales.
You think we didn't jump out of the plane because of a light breeze?
Crois-tu qu'on s'empךchait de sauter pour un peu de vent ?
You're in this shit now, Mustache!
Tu es dans la merde, la moustache !
I'm only yelling to impress the other guys.
Je crie pour impressionner les autres.
I'd never let anything happen to you, Sugarbear.
Je te protיgerai, mon nounours.
Leonard, hit it!
Leonard, appuie sur le bouton !
Go! Go! Go!
Allez ! Allez !
Let's get some!
Allons-y !
Oh, yeah!
Oh, ouais !
Convoy, 12 o'clock! On my command!
Convoi א 12 h ! ְ mon signal !
Deploy! Hey now!
Dיploiement ! Oh, hי !
Little off course here.
J'ai dיviי un tout petit peu.
Holy mommy fucking shit!
Bon Dieu de merde !
There they are.
Les voilא.
Look at these gorgeous sons of bitches.
Regardez cette bande de beaux salauds.
Oh, yeah! That's right, Bedlam!
Oh, oui ! C'est חa, Bedlam !
No! Tripping motherfucking billies!
Non ! Saloperie !
Shatterstar. Okay, you got this.
Shatterstar. ְ toi de jouer.
Left!
ְ gauche !
No, stage left, you idiot!
Cפtי cour, imbיcile !
Well, I guess we found something you're not better at.
Voilא un truc pour lequel tu n'es pas le meilleur.
Vanisher.
Fantפme.
Maybe the wind can't blow what it can't see.
Le vent n'emporte pas ce qu'il ne voit pas.
Really?
Vraiment ?
All right, we could do this with four.
Bon, on peut rיussir חa א quatre.
Sugarbear. You got this, buddy!
Mon nounours. Tu peux y arriver !
That's the stuff! That's the X-Force spirit!
C'est חa ! C'est l'esprit de la X-Force !
Never underestimate a man with a mustache!
Ne sous-estimez jamais un moustachu.
Just ask anyone in Brooklyn.
Demandez א quiconque א Brooklyn.
- We did it! - You're a goddamn superhero, you!
- On a rיussi ! - Tu es un superhיros !
X-Force!
X-Force !
X-Force.
X-Force.
Peter.
Peter.
- I got you, buddy! You're gonna be fine! - This is not good, man!
- Je te tiens ! Tu vas t'en tirer ! - C'est grave !
You got this, big guy! Here we go, Peter!
Tu vas y arriver, mon grand ! Allez, Peter !
Look at me. We're X-Force, right?
Regarde-moi. On est la X-Force.
- Yeah, we're X-Force. - We're X-Force.
- Oui, la X-Force. - La X-Force.
Oh, my God! What the fuck?
Mon Dieu ! C'est quoi, חa ?
Fucking acidic vomit!
Foutu vomi acide !
Oh, God! I'm gonna throw up in my mask.
Mon Dieu ! Je vais vomir dans mon masque.
Okay, I'm over the convoy.
Je survole le convoi.
Where did the rest of the team land?
Oש est le reste de l'יquipe ?
Good news and bad news.
J'ai une bonne et une mauvaise nouvelle.
Bad news is the whole team is dead.
La mauvaise, c'est que toute l'יquipe est morte.
The good news is, I don't think anyone's gonna miss Shatterstar.
La bonne, c'est que personne ne s'ennuiera de Shatterstar.
He was a bit of a prick. Oh, but Paul!
C'יtait un enfoirי. Oh, mais Paul !
- Peter! - Peter, I'm gonna miss him most.
- Peter ! - Peter me manquera le plus.
But there is a slight chance Vanisher could make it.
Il reste une chance que Fantפme s'en sorte.
Nope, no chance. He's dead.
Non, il est mort.
The whole team?
Toute l'יquipe ?
Only the main ones. We're still good.
Juste les principaux. ַa ira.
Fuck, you are dumb.
Ce que tu es idiot.
Even after all this time, I still can't talk about it.
Mךme aprטs tout ce temps, je ne peux pas en parler.
Who knew these winds would be so strong?
Qui et cru que le vent serait si fort ?
Everyone! Everyone on the helicopter!
Tout le monde dans l'hיlicoptטre !
And everyone not on the helicopter!
Et hors de l'hיlicoptטre !
They're headed into the tunnel.
Ils entrent dans le tunnel.
I'm that kid's only hope, so sit tight and wait for my word.
Je suis le seul espoir du petit, alors attends mes ordres.
Whatever. We're gonna lose 'em. I'm dropping in.
N'importe quoi. On les perdra de vue. J'y vais.
That's a negative, sole survivor.
Nיgatif, seule survivante.
Luck is not a superpower! We are so fucked!
La chance n'est pas un pouvoir ! On est foutus !
No, we most certainly are not fucked.
On n'est certainement pas foutus.
Seriously, I don't get it!
Je ne comprends pas !
What, you shoot luck lasers out of your eyes?
Tes yeux tirent des lasers chanceux ?
It's just it's hard to picture.
C'est difficile א imaginer.
And certainly not very cinematic.
Et pas trטs cinיmatographique.
I mean, luck?
La chance ?
What coked out, glass pipe-sucking freakshow comic book artist...
Quel genre d'enfoirי droguי de dessinateur de bיdי א la con
came up with that little chestnut?
a trouvי cette petite perle ?
Probably a guy who can't draw feet!
Un gars qui ne sait pas dessiner les pieds, je parie !
Once again, it all falls on my shoulders.
Tout retombe sur moi une fois de plus.
It's why I'm cursed to be a solo act. Wander the Earth...
Condamnי א agir seul. ְ errer...
- I'm in. - I'm sorry, what did you say?
- J'y suis. - Pardon, quoi ?
- How in the fuck are you in already?
- Comment peux-tu y ךtre ?
Oh, shit.
Oh, merde.
It's Cable. 12 o'clock.
C'est Cable, א 12 h.
Okay.
D'accord.
New plan. Use all of your imaginary powers to stop Cable from killing that kid.
Nouveau plan. Avec tes pouvoirs imaginaires,
I'm coming up on your six.
J'arrive derriטre toi.
That gun is amazing!
C'est gיnial, cette arme !
Hey! Asshole!
Hי ! Enfoirי !
Where is he? I can't see him.
Oש est-il ? Je ne le vois pas.
He's on top of you.
Par-dessus toi.
He's going in through the back!
Il va pיnיtrer par-derriטre !
Oh, God, he's inside!
Il est א l'intיrieur !
You hear yourself, right?
T'entends-tu parler ?
Accidental double entendres!
Ce n'יtait pas voulu !
Russell! Russell Collins!
Russell ! Russell Collins !
Hands off that kid, John Connor!
Ne touche pas, א l'enfant, John Connor !
No, no, no!
Non, non, non !
Shit!
Merde !
Two can play that game!
Ce petit jeu se joue א deux !
Got it! No, I don't.
Je l'ai ! Ou pas.
Showtime, mama!
ְ toi de jouer, ma belle !
Lady Luck, take the wheel.
ְ toi de conduire, la chance.
I'd ask who you are, but you'll be dead in a second.
Je te demanderais qui tu es, mais tu vas mourir.
I'm Domino, and doubtful.
Domino, et j'en doute.
Hang in there, Doms!
Tiens bon, Doms !
This is really hard.
C'est vraiment dur.
And give me back my Skee-Ball token.
Redonne-moi mon jeton de fךte foraine.
- You're doing great. - X-Force.
- Tu t'en tires bien. - X-Force.
I guess dubstep never dies.
Le dubstep ne meurt jamais.
You killed Black Tom, you racist son of a bitch!
Tu as tuי Tom le Noir, sale raciste !
That's unfortunate.
C'est malheureux.
We got no brakes!
Les freins sont fichus !
Figure it out!
Trouve une solution !
There's nothing I can't kill.
Je peux tout tuer.
Somebody knows karate.
Quelqu'un connaמt le karatי.
Give me your best shot, One-Eyed Willy.
Montre-moi ce que tu sais faire.
Here we go.
C'est parti.
Domino, mind slowing us down?
Domino, peux-tu nous ralentir ?
Here goes nothing.
Je peux bien essayer.
Knock, knock.
Toc-toc.
That's my boy.
C'est bien, petit.
Holy...
Bordel...
I'll be first to admit...
Je suis le premier א admettre
this did not go according to plan.
que חa ne s'est pas passי selon le plan.
I'll also be the first to admit that that plan was written in crayon.
Je suis aussi le premier א admettre qu'on avait un plan au crayon de cire.
Looks like Russell found a new friend. Jelly.
Russell a un nouvel ami. Je suis jaloux.
Turns out Domino's a bit of a badass, and maybe, possibly mildly lucky.
Domino est une vraie dure, et possiblement plutפt chanceuse.
But Cable? That guy's in a mood.
Mais Cable ? Il est de mauvaise humeur.
A mood that is about to get significantly worse.
Humeur qui s'apprךte א empirer considיrablement.
Something is so terribly, terribly wrong.
ַa ne va pas du tout.
Oh, God, that hurt.
Mon Dieu, חa a fait mal.
Russell.
Russell.
Russell!
Russell !
Russ, where are ya?
Russ, oש es-tu ?
Russell. Russell, you're okay!
Russell. Russell, tu n'as rien !
Oh, thank God. Oh, my God!
Dieu merci. Oh, mon Dieu !
Juggernaut!
Le Flיau !
I thought that was you!
Je croyais bien que c'יtait toi !
I should've worn my white pants.
J'aurais d mettre mon pantalon blanc.
You probably get this a lot, but I am a huge fan.
On te le dit srement souvent, mais je t'admire יnormיment.
Uncanny X-Men 183. Thor 411.
Uncanny X-Men 183. Thor411.
X-Men Unlimited 12.
X-Men Unlimited 12.
You know, it has always been a dream of mine...
J'ai toujours rךvי de voir
to see my face reflected in your helmet...
mon visage reflיtי sur ton casque
as you charge at me with murderous intent.
alors que tu fonחais pour me tuer.
I don't mean right now.
Pas nיcessairement maintenant.
I'm gonna rip you in half now.
Je vais te dיchiqueter.
That is such a Juggernaut thing to say.
Je te reconnais bien lא, le Flיau.
Oh, my God! I can't feel my legs.
Mon Dieu ! Je ne sens plus mes jambes.
I can't feel...
Je ne sens plus...
Oh, no, they're right here.
Oh, non, elles sont lא.
Got 'em. God, Russell.
Je les ai. Seigneur, Russell.
I have a mission.
J'ai une mission.
To get my revenge.
Je vais me venger.
I'm going to burn that headmaster alive.
Le directeur sera brlי vif.
You're not the revenge type.
Tu n'es pas du genre א te venger.
Take it from a friend.
Crois-en un ami.
Friend? You were sick, and I protected you.
Ami ? Tu יtais malade, et je t'ai protיgי.
You said it yourself.
Tu l'as dit toi-mךme.
"I'm not your friend. Find someone stronger."
"Je ne suis pas ton ami. Trouves-en un plus fort."
So I did.
Je l'ai donc fait.
Russell, I couldn't protect you back then.
Je ne pouvais pas te protיger alors,
But I can now. What do you want me to say?
mais maintenant, oui. Qu'aimerais-tu entendre ?
"I care about you"? 'Cause goddamn it, I care about you, Russell.
"Je me soucie de toi ?" Parce que je me soucie de toi, Russell.
What's Juggernaut got that I don't have?
Qu'a le Flיau que je n'ai pas ?
Don't you say legs! I know you're gonna say legs!
Ne dis pas des jambes ! Je sais que tu vas dire חa !
- Legs! - Still hurts to hear out loud!
- Des jambes ! - ַa fait mal de l'entendre !
What is that? That's not a real rope!
C'est quoi, חa ? Ce n'est pas une vraie corde !
You get back here, young man!
Reviens ici, petit !
Doms!
Doms !
Doms, get me out of here, please.
Doms, emmטne-moi loin d'ici.
Use my arms as backpack straps.
Sers-toi de mes bras comme des bretelles de sac.
I think we may have found your cosmic reason for being here.
Je crois qu'on a trouvי la raison cosmique de ta prיsence.
I'm pretty sure this isn't it.
Je doute que ce soit חa.
X-Force.
X-Force.
No child is hopeless.
Aucun enfant n'est une cause perdue.
- Don't give up on the boy. - How could he just walk away?
- Ne le laisse pas tomber. - Comment a-t-il pu partir ?
It was the coldness in his eyes.
Son regard יtait si froid.
You should've heard it.
Tu aurais d l'entendre.
I guess family really is an F-word.
"Famille" est bel et bien un gros mot.
Rub my legs, Mama.
Frotte mes jambes.
Why would I rub your legs?
Pourquoi ferais-je חa ?
Please, they hurt. I have growing pains.
Elles me font mal. Des douleurs de croissance.
What in the...
Qu'est-ce que...
Why is your hand so tiny again?
Pourquoi ta main est-elle minuscule, dיjא ?
That's not my hand.
Ce n'est pas ma main.
Mary, mother of Joseph!
Oh ! Jיsus Marie Joseph !
That was nice for me.
ַa m'a fait du bien.
Wade! I heard what happened with the convoy and...
Wade ! J'ai su ce qui יtait arrivי au convoi et...
Why wouldn't you cover that up?
Tu peux cacher חa ?
A warrior has nothing to be ashamed of.
Un guerrier n'a pas de raison d'avoir honte.
Yeah, but you do. Look at you.
Mais toi, oui. Regarde-toi.
You're just straight shirt-cocking it, toddler-style.
Tu traמnes carrיment la bite א l'air, comme un bambin.
Oh, yeah. Full Winnie the Pooh.
Oh, oui. Comme Winnie l'Ourson.
The hell's happening? Describe it.
Qu'est-ce qui se passe ? Dיcris-le.
I wouldn't ask him to do that, if I were you.
Ne lui demande pas חa.
- It's like... - Here we go.
- C'est... - Et voilא.
It's like he was giving birth anally, but they quit halfway through.
Comme s'il accouchait par l'anus et avait abandonnי en route.
They got the legs out, and they said, "You know what, I'm done."
Les jambes sont sorties, et il a arrךtי lא.
Happy?
- Contente ? - On dirait une marionnette.
But this time, you can see the Muppet's dick.
Mais une marionnette la bite א l'air.
Grover's got a cock the size of a twig.
- Grosse comme une brindille. - M. Weasel, je dois bouger l'auto.
I've had three tickets already.
J'ai eu trois contraventions.
No, no, no, DP, not again!
Non, DP, pas encore !
This has happened before?
C'est dיjא arrivי ?
Jesus! Either vomit or don't. The indecision is killing me.
Seigneur ! Vomis ou pas. L'indיcision me tue.
Why couldn't God take my hearing?
Dieu aurait pu me priver d'ouןe.
Wow!
Ouah !
Cool your pits. They're growing back.
Du calme. ַa va repousser.
I'm talking about your face.
Je parle de ton visage.
I've never seen you without your mask before.
Je ne t'avais pas vu sans masque.
- Jesus Christ! - Looks like an avocado.
- Seigneur ! - On dirait un avocat.
Your legs, though, they're cute.
Mais tes jambes sont mignonnes.
You wanna borrow a pair of pants?
Veux-tu emprunter un pantalon ?
I'm glad everybody dropped by.
Content que vous soyez lא.
You must be wondering why I didn't call you here.
On se demande pourquoi je ne vous ai pas invitיs.
I'll tell you why I'm here.
Je vais te dire ce que je fais ici.
"The Time Traveler's Wife's" husband...
Monsieur "Le temps n'est rien"
beat me within an inch of my life. He was torturing me!
a failli me battre א mort. Il m'a torturי !
But all I told him was everything he wanted to know.
Je lui ai seulement dit tout ce qu'il voulait savoir.
So, I'm here to help us gear up.
Je suis ici pour vous יquiper
- So we can go after him without me. - No!
- afin que vous le pourchassiez sans moi. - Non !
I'm doing this alone.
J'irai seul.
- The Juggernaut will kill you all. - Fair enough.
- Le Flיau vous tuera tous. - Bien dit.
I just need a couple of hours to get some legs under me.
Il faut seulement que mes jambes repoussent.
What will you do?
Que ferez-vous ?
I don't care what the kid did to me.
Je me fiche de ce que le petit m'a fait.
I ain't letting Cable get to him, even if I have to teabag him to death.
J'arrךterai Cable mךme si je dois l'יtouffer avec mon entrejambe.
It's really just a sip of tea at this point.
Il n'y a pas grand-chose avec quoi s'יtouffer.
Zip it, black Black Widow! I'm flowing.
La ferme, Veuve Noire noire ! ַa pousse.
The first order of business is to get me in front of Cable...
Pour commencer, je retrouverai Cable
so I can pull all the fucking blood out of his body...
pour le saigner א blanc
and fashion his bones into holiday jewelry.
et faire des bijoux avec ses os.
Then, I'm gonna take his skin...
Aprטs, je prendrai sa peau
and stretch it out over a homemade mating drum.
et j'en ferai un tambour nuptial artisanal.
He's standing right behind you, isn't he?
Il est derriטre vous, hein ?
What in the ass?
C'est quoi, ce bordel ?
Is this apartment listed on Tinder? Grindr?
L'appartement est sur Tinder ? Sur Grindr ?
You picked the wrong shithole to fuck, future boy.
Tu as choisi le mauvais trou א baiser.
Is that really necessary?
Est-ce bien nיcessaire ?
No. It's his "Basic Instinct."
Non. C'est son moment Basic Instinct.
What can we help you with?
Que peut-on pour toi ?
I'm here to proposition you.
J'ai une proposition.
Oh, boy! He's really teeing it up, isn't he?
Bon sang ! Il rend חa trop facile.
Who gets to make the first joke?
Qui fera la premiטre blague ?
I think we should all do it at the same time.
Allons-y tous ensemble.
Good call.
Bonne idיe.
For $45, you get sucky-suck.
C'est 45 $ la pipe.
- I only do over the pants, mouth stuff. - Fuck!
- Par-dessus le pantalon. - Merde !
The Proposition has a wonderful Guy Pearce performance.
The Proposition, touchante interprיtation de Guy Pearce.
Wait, wait, wait! I wanna do mine over.
Attendez ! Je veux recommencer.
- Give us the line again. - I need your help!
- Reprenons la rיplique. - J'ai besoin d'aide !
Trust me, I'm even less happy about this than you are...
ַa ne me plaמt pas plus qu'א toi,
but you unleashed the Juggernaut, you dumb cunt!
mais tu as libיrי le Flיau, pauvre con !
I can't bring him down alone.
Je ne peux pas l'יliminer seul.
So here we are.
Voilא oש on en est.
We're no longer accepting applications for X-Force, unfortunately.
On n'accepte plus de candidats dans la X-Force, dommage.
Even if we were...
Mךme si on en acceptait,
there's a wind advisory in effect until at least...
l'avertissement de vent reste en vigueur.
We don't have a lot of time.
On a peu de temps.
Your friend's about to make his first kill.
Ton ami va commettre son premier meurtre.
No offense, but if you know so much...
Si tu sais tout חa,
why not travel back to when he was a baby, kill him then?
retourne א l'יpoque oש il יtait bיbי et tue-le.
Or better yet, head back a little further, kill baby Hitler.
Mieux encore, retourne tuer le bיbי Hitler.
I use a device to slide through time.
J'ai un dispositif de voyage dans le temps.
The longer I travel, the harder it is to control.
Plus je vais loin, plus c'est dur א maמtriser.
I got two charges: one to get me here, one to get me home.
J'ai deux charges : une pour venir ici, une pour rentrer.
That's just lazy writing.
Les scיnaristes sont paresseux.
Your boy's gonna kill the headmaster of the orphanage tonight.
Le petit tuera le directeur de l'orphelinat ce soir.
After that, he gets a real taste for it.
Aprטs, il y prendra got.
Like 10-year-old Kirsten Dunst, motherfucker!
Comme la petite Kirsten Dunst !
So he keeps killing...
Il continuera א tuer
and killing, and killing, and killing.
et א tuer, et א tuer, et א tuer.
Until one day, he kills the wrong fucking people.
Jusqu'au jour oש il tuera les mauvaises personnes.
My people.
Mes proches.
Relax.
Du calme.
I'm retrieving something from my utility bag.
Je cherche un truc dans mon sac utilitaire.
It's a goddamn fanny pack...
C'est un sac banane
and you know it, you sick son of a bitch!
et tu le sais, enfoirי !
The difference is night and day.
C'est aussi diffיrent que la nuit et le jour.
You remind me of my wife.
Tu me rappelles ma femme.
I'm sorry.
Je regrette.
- I said, "You remind me of my wife." - No, I'm sorry that you said that...
- Tu me rappelles ma femme. - Je regrette que tu aies dit חa
while making heavy eye contact and applying lip balm.
les yeux rivיs sur les miens, en mettant du baume א lטvres.
She always struggled.
Elle avait la vie dure.
But she was funny...
Mais elle יtait drפle
and filtered her pain through the prism of humor.
et gardait le sens de l'humour malgrי sa douleur.
Something I could never master.
Je n'ai jamais su faire de mךme.
It was my fault she died.
Elle est morte par ma faute.
It was my job to stop people like him.
C'יtait mon travail d'arrךter les gens comme lui.
I came close a few times.
Je suis passי prטs.
He wasn't too happy about that.
ַa l'a mis en colטre.
He was trying to hurt me...
Il voulait se venger
and he knew exactly how to do it.
et savait exactement comment faire.
Blessed are the wicked who are healed by my hand.
Bיnis sont les dיviants qui sont guיris par ma main.
He came into my home...
Il est venu chez moi
and took the only thing that made it a home.
et m'a enlevי la seule chose qui en faisait mon chez-moi.
Sound familiar?
ַa te semble familier ?
I'm sorry.
Je suis dיsolי.
No, I'm really sorry.
Non, sincטrement.
But that isn't Russell.
Mais ce n'est pas Russell.
- It doesn't have to be him. - If you knew what I knew...
- Pas forcיment. - Si tu savais...
Yeah, he's got anger issues...
Il a du mal א gיrer sa colטre,
maybe a small learning disability...
des difficultיs d'apprentissage,
splash of diabetes...
un soupחon de diabטte,
- but nothing that can't be fixed. - If you could go back...
- mais חa peut s'arranger. - Si tu pouvais retourner
and stop the people that took your girl, would you?
arrךter ceux qui t'ont pris ta femme, le ferais-tu ?
Of course I fucking would!
Bien sr que oui !
But I wouldn't kill a kid.
Mais je ne tuerais pas un enfant.
I'm not asking you to kill a kid! I'll kill the kid.
Je ne te demande pas חa ! Je le tuerai, moi.
I'm asking you to save hundreds of other kids.
Je te demande de sauver des centaines d'enfants.
Russell's gonna burn down that orphanage.
Russell va faire brler tout l'orphelinat.
And I can imagine your dead girlfriend...
J'imagine que ta dיfunte femme
would want you to do the right thing, wouldn't she?
voudrait que tu fasses le bon choix.
So, what's it gonna be, handsome?
Alors que choisis-tu, mon beau ?
Give me a chance to save him.
Donne-moi une chance de le sauver.
- What? - You said...
- Quoi ? - Tu as dit
once he kills someone, he gets a taste for it.
qu'il prendrait got א tuer.
If we can get to him before that happens...
Si on rיussit א l'arrךter avant,
promise you'll give me a chance to put him on a different path.
promets de me laisser la chance de l'orienter sur une autre voie.
Define "chance."
Dיfinis "chance".
I don't know. How long does it take to save someone's soul? That's not...
Combien de temps faut-il pour sauver une גme ?
I'll give you 30 seconds.
Tu auras 30 secondes.
- What? No! - Best I can do.
- Quoi ? Non ! - Meilleure offre.
Take it or leave it.
ְ prendre ou א laisser.
He's doing it!
Il le fait !
Look at the little fella. He's doing it.
Regardez-le. Il y arrive.
There he goes.
C'est חa.
Jesus Christ!
Seigneur !
Just shirt-cocking it.
La bite א l'air.
There you go, little fella.
Vas-y, petit.
Go on, you're doing it!
Allez, tu y arrives !
My beautiful, hairless, Twizzler-legged baby boy.
Mon beau bיbי aux jambes en rיglisse.
Christ!
Bon Dieu !
That's disturbing.
C'est troublant.
30 seconds.
Trente secondes.
- Deal.
- Marchי conclu.
I have no idea what's happening.
Je ne sais pas ce qui se passe.
Probably for the best.
C'est pour le mieux.
And that is why you never eat a raw starfish.
On ne doit donc pas manger d'יtoile de mer crue.
It's just common sense.
C'est le gros bon sens.
Where the hell are we going?
Oש est-ce qu'on va ?
You said it yourself.
Tu l'as dit.
Nothing can stop the Juggernaut. We need backup.
Rien n'arrךte le Flיau. Il faut des renforts.
I will bathe in the blood of your enemies.
Je me baignerai dans le sang de vos ennemis.
Can you turn off the music?
Peux-tu יteindre la musique ?
You'll do no such thing.
Tu ne feras pas חa.
Why don't you just say it in an Indian accent?
Dis-le donc avec un accent indien.
What the hell are you...?
Qu'est-ce que tu...
Once again, intolerance rears its ugly head.
L'intolיrance montre son affreux visage.
I am so sorry. It gets better.
Je suis navrי. ַa s'amיliorera.
I'm not a fucking racist, moron!
Je ne suis pas raciste, imbיcile !
Tell that to Black Tom. He was like a brother to me.
Dis חa א Tom le Noir. C'יtait mon frטre.
I'm with the old white guy on this one. And that's a twist.
Je suis d'accord avec le vieux Blanc. C'est surprenant.
So what exactly do you do in the future, anyway? Some kind of soldier?
Que fais-tu dans l'avenir, au juste ? Es-tu soldat ?
Yeah, something like that.
Quelque chose comme חa.
I was a soldier. Special Forces.
J'ai יtי soldat. Forces spיciales.
I bet 50 years from now, we're bestest buddies.
Je parie que dans 50 ans, on sera de grands amis.
50 years from now, you're very dead.
Dans 50 ans, tu seras mort.
Your entire generation fucked this planet into a coma.
Ta gיnיration aura mis la planטte dans le coma.
Boom!
Boum !
Spoiler alert.
Alerte au divulgגcheur.
Planets.
Les planטtes.
Next time, Uber.
Prochaine fois, un Uber.
Here's a spoiler alert.
J'ai une alerte pour toi.
You're not a fucking hero.
Tu n'es pas un hיros.
You're just an annoying clown dressed up as a sex toy.
Tu n'es qu'un clown costumי en jouet sexuel.
Well, I got news for you. My heart is in the right place.
Sache une chose. Mon cur est א la bonne place.
Russell's not gonna kill anyone.
Russell ne tuera personne.
Because of me, he's gonna know what real love looks like.
Grגce א moi, il saura ce qu'est l'amour.
Because of you, I'll always know what a grown man with baby balls looks like.
Grגce א toi, je sais א quoi ressemble un homme aux couilles de bיbי.
I'm a grower, not a shower.
Elles sont discrטtes, mais puissantes.
I should've finished college.
J'aurais d rester aux יtudes.
Right here!
C'est ici !
I made mistakes!
J'ai commis des erreurs !
I wanna take them back!
Je veux me racheter !
You trusted me. I took that trust...
Tu me faisais confiance,
and turned it into a glory hole in an airport bathroom.
et j'ai fait de ta confiance un trou de baise dans une toilette d'aיroport.
The one in Minneapolis. You know the one.
ְ Minneapolis. Tu sais laquelle.
Colossus!
Colossus !
I wouldn't ask for your help unless it was life or death!
C'est une question de vie ou de mort !
That kid needs our help!
Le petit a besoin de nous !
I know you're listening!
Je sais que tu m'entends !
He's teamed up with the Juggernaut! The Juggernaut!
Il s'est alliי au Flיau ! Le seul et unique Flיau !
That's like my favorite Marvel character ever,
C'est mon personnage de Marvel prיfיrי,
but you should never meet your heroes...
mais on ne devrait pas rencontrer ses hיros,
And like a lot of dicks, he's as hard as a rock...
Une vraie tךte de gland, dure comme la roche
and causes nothing but problems!
et qui ne cause que des ennuis !
- Hi, Wade! - Hi, Yukio!
- Salut, Wade ! - Salut, Yukio !
- Please don't. - You guys make a super cute couple.
- Ne fais pas חa. - Vous faites un beau couple.
Yeah. Where was I? Oh, yeah!
Oש en יtais-je ? Ah, oui !
Colossus! Look, I don't deserve your friendship or your help.
Colossus ! Je sais que je ne mיrite ni ton amitiי ni ton aide.
But this kid does.
Mais le petit, oui.
And I'm not gonna bail on him like everyone else.
Je ne le laisserai pas tomber comme tous les autres.
Oh, come on!
Oh, allez !
Any chance Pigeon Wings is available?
Ailes de Pigeon est-il libre, א tout hasard ?
That's just fine! That's fine!
ַa va ! ַa va !
No! You know what?
Non ! Tu sais quoi ?
Doing the right thing is sometimes messy...
Faire le bon choix, c'est parfois bordיlique,
and fucked up, and not particularly convenient!
dיroutant et pas trטs pratique !
So stay here in Château de Virgin...
Alors, reste ici au palais des vierges
while we go get our fuck on!
pendant qu'on va foutre la merde !
You're doing great.
Tu fais bien חa.
So you wear that helmet because your brother tries to read your mind?
Tu portes un casque parce que ton frטre lit tes pensיes ?
Yeah, but he's in a wheelchair, so even-steven.
On est quittes. Il est en fauteuil roulant.
Someone's coming. It's Russell, sir.
Quelqu'un arrive. C'est Russell.
He's not alone.
Il n'est pas seul.
Secure the children.
Mets les enfants en sretי.
What do you say we go fuck some shit up?
ַa te dit de foutre le bordel ?
"Let's fuck some shit up" is my legal middle name.
"Foutre le bordel" est mon deuxiטme prיnom.
Watch my back. I've got the old man.
Surveille mes arriטres. Je m'occupe du vieux.
Amen, brother.
Amen, mon frטre.
Time to make the chimichangas.
Ils vont bouffer du gיnיral K.O.
30 seconds.
Trente secondes.
I finally know why I'm here.
Je sais enfin ce que je fais ici.
I was raised in this place.
J'ai יtי יlevיe dans cet endroit.
Well, not raised. I was tortured.
Enfin, pas יlevיe. Plutפt torturיe.
Wow! It's your cosmic reason for being here.
Ouah ! Ta raison cosmique d'ךtre ici.
- Shall we? - This is gonna be fun.
- On y va ? - On va s'amuser.
Yeah!
Ouais !
Hey! Been meaning to ask you...
Hי ! Je voulais te demander,
what's with the creepy, dirty hobo bear?
c'est quoi, cet ours tout sale qui fait peur ?
It's not dirt. It's the blood of my dead daughter.
Il n'est pas sale. C'est le sang de ma fille.
I have a gluten sensitivity.
Je suis sensible au gluten.
So one glass of wine, I just...
Un seul verre de vin et je...
Yeah.
Oui.
Wish we could head back in time, and I could take all that back.
Je voudrais remonter le temps et ne pas dire חa.
We should just cue the music.
Envoyez la musique.
Welcome home, Russell. We missed you.
Bienvenue chez toi, Russell. Tu nous as manquי.
Russell!
Russell !
You don't need to do this! Let's talk!
Tu n'as pas besoin de faire חa ! Discutons !
Why are you dressed like the Unabomber?
Pourquoi es-tu habillי en terroriste ?
That's why!
- Voilא pourquoi ! - Je savais qu'il יtait trop tard.
Zip it, Thanos! We have a deal and you fuck...
La ferme, Thanos ! On a un marchי et tu...
Hey!
Hי !
I'm gonna shove that cab driver right up your ass.
Je t'enfoncerai ce chauffeur de taxi dans le cul.
My body and my hands are so soft.
Mon corps et mes mains sont si doux.
- You should probably head back to the car. - I think I'll head back to the car.
- Retourne dans l'auto. - Je retourne dans l'auto.
It works best when you pull the trigger.
ַa va mieux quand on appuie sur la dיtente.
That gun is amazing!
C'est incroyable !
Say it!
Dites-le !
You are an abomination!
Tu es une abomination !
Now, I'm gonna shove the red guy up the old guy.
Je vais enfoncer le rouge dans le vieux.
I believe him! Every man for themselves!
Je le crois ! Chacun pour soi !
Gotcha!
Je te tiens !
Beat it, midget!
Dיgage, minable !
Hey, big guy, the sun's getting real low!
Dis, le gros, le soleil va se coucher !
Shit fuck!
Oh, merde !
Come here, beautiful.
Approche, beautי.
Say it!
Dites-le !
You came for me.
Tu es venu.
I'm not giving up on you, and you are not giving up on that boy.
Je ne t'abandonnerai pas et tu n'abandonneras pas le petit.
Who says that rules aren't meant to be broken?
Qui dit que les rטgles, חa ne s'enfreint pas ?
It's time to fight dirty.
C'est l'heure des coups bas.
Time to sweep the leg, Johnny.
Vise les jambes, Johnny.
Hey! Pick on someone your own size!
Hי ! Attaque-toi א quelqu'un de ta taille !
That's such a you thing to say! Go get him, tiger!
Je te reconnais bien lא ! Vas-y, champion !
Big CGI fight coming up!
Un gros combat en images de synthטses !
He's doing great.
Il s'en tire bien.
Say it!
Dites-le !
- Russell. - Bingo!
- Russell. - Bingo !
That's right! I'm fighting dirty!
C'est חa ! Des coups bas !
- Oh, great! - There they are! Those freaks!
- Oh, super ! - Ils sont lא !
A bunch of armed pedophiles in nursing shoes.
Des pיdos armיs en chaussures d'infirmiers.
Can I have one of those guns?
Je peux avoir une arme comme חa ?
- No. - That's fine.
- Non. - Tant pis.
Get off this property, mutant scum!
Partez d'ici, saloperies de mutants !
I'm just gonna use this brick.
Une brique fera l'affaire.
Maximum effort.
Avec un maximum d'efforts.
Who says you can't go home again?
Qui dit qu'on ne rentre jamais chez soi ?
Yeah!
Ouais !
Say it.
Dites-le.
Say what you said every time you tortured me!
Dites ce que vous disiez en me torturant !
Say it!
Dites-le !
Blessed are the wicked who are healed by my hand!
Bיnis sont les dיviants qui sont guיris par ma main !
who are healed...
qui sont guיris
by my hand.
par ma main.
You commie motherfucker!
Sale communiste !
Oh, my God. Did you feel that, too?
Oh, mon Dieu. L'as-tu senti aussi ?
Only best buddies execute pedophiles together.
Seuls les grands amis tuent des pיdophiles ensemble.
You got 30 seconds, you jabbering butt plug!
Tu as 30 secondes, le suppositoire parlant !
Now we're getting it.
Enfin, on se comprend.
I need a bus to get you all out of here.
Il me faut un autobus pour vous sortir d'ici.
Orphans.
Par ici, les orphelins.
Oh, geez.
Oh, bon sang.
It's time to burn for what you've done!
Vous mיritez de brler pour ce que vous avez fait !
A child should not be burdened with such power!
Un enfant ne devrait pas avoir de tels pouvoirs !
Russell! Wait!
Russell ! Attends !
Wait! He hasn't killed anyone yet!
Attends ! Il n'a encore tuי personne !
- What more do you need to see? - Don't you fucking dare!
- Que veux-tu voir de plus ? - N'ose pas !
He's just a kid!
Ce n'est qu'un enfant !
Tick, tock. Meter's running!
Tic-tac. Le temps file !
I'm gonna melt you down and make a cock ring.
Je vais te transformer en anneau א bite.
- I told you! Leave me alone! - Come on!
- Laisse-moi tranquille ! - Allez !
Listen to me!
ֹcoute-moi !
That's how we do it in Mother Russia.
On fait comme חa en Russie.
They say millennials are the hardest to reach.
C'est dur de toucher les enfants du millיnaire.
Oh, no. You're doing amazing.
Oh, non. Tu te dיbrouilles א merveille.
Damn, it feels good to be a gangsta!
ַa fait du bien d'ךtre un gangster !
Go home, Wade!
Rentre chez toi, Wade !
You're ruining everything!
Tu gגches tout !
I'm getting good at this shit.
Je m'amיliore.
Go, go, go!
Allez, allez !
He dies tonight, Wade.
Il va mourir ce soir, Wade.
You can't stop me!
Tu ne peux pas m'arrךter !
He even runs like a fucking pervert.
Il court mךme comme un pervers.
Like an online predator who lost his laptop.
Comme un prיdateur en ligne qui a perdu son portable.
There's one bullet left in that gun.
Il me reste une balle.
Wait, wait, wait! Please, just give me a second!
Attends ! Donne-moi une seconde !
I got this.
Je m'occupe de tout.
- Russell! - Stay back! Go home, Wade!
- Russell ! - N'avance pas ! Pars, Wade !
Let's talk. It doesn't have to go this way!
ַa n'est pas obligי de se passer comme חa !
That piece of shit...
Ce salaud mיrite
he deserves to die for what he did to you.
de mourir pour ce qu'il t'a fait.
He hurt you badly. Makes you wanna hurt others.
Il t'a fait du mal. Tu veux faire de mךme.
But if you kill him, he wins.
Mais si tu le tues, il gagne.
You become everything he says you are, but worse.
Tu deviens ce qu'il dit que tu es, en pire.
You're just a kid.
Tu n'es qu'un garחon.
You don't wanna hurt anyone.
Tu ne veux de mal א personne.
How do you know what I want?
Comment sais-tu ce que je veux ?
Because I've been inside you.
J'ai יtי en toi.
That came out wrong.
ַa sonne mal.
I've been inside your shoes.
J'ai יtי dans tes souliers.
Which is also off-putting.
Pas gיnial non plus.
It's not a great analogy.
Ce n'est pas une belle analogie.
The point is...
J'essaie de dire
there are people...
qu'il y a des gens...
There are people in this fucking world...
Il y a des gens dans ce foutu monde,
besides him, who will treat you right.
א part lui, qui te traiteront bien.
It isn't too late. Don't do it.
Il n'est pas trop tard. Ne le fais pas.
I never should've left you there.
Je n'aurais pas d te laisser lא-bas.
I never should've left you in that prison.
Je n'aurais pas d te laisser en prison.
I can't trust you.
Je n'ai pas confiance en toi.
I can't trust anybody!
Je n'ai confiance en personne !
Wonderful kid.
Charmant garחon.
You can't stop me, Wade!
Tu ne m'arrךteras pas, Wade !
I got one more idea.
J'ai une autre idיe.
It's just a really bad one, even for me.
Elle est trטs mauvaise, mךme pour moi.
Wade, what are you doing?
Wade, que fais-tu ?
All right. This is for all the marbles, kid!
C'est ta derniטre chance, petit !
You're gonna kill someone today...
Si tu dois tuer quelqu'un aujourd'hui...
Blessed are the wicked...
Bיnis sont les dיviants...
...then it's gotta be me.
... ce sera moi.
...who are healed by my hand!
... qui sont guיris par ma main.
Fuck this!
Et puis merde !
Tell me they got that in slow motion.
Dites-moi qu'on a filmי חa au ralenti.
That's not good.
ַa augure mal.
No, sir.
Trטs mal.
You sacrificed yourself for me.
Tu t'es sacrifiי pour moi.
Yeah.
Oui.
And it was the best thing I ever did.
Et c'est la meilleure chose que j'aie faite.
I told you I care about you.
Je t'ai dit que je me souciais de toi.
You're a good kid, Russell.
Tu es quelqu'un de bien, Russell.
Hey.
Hי !
The bear.
L'ourson.
It worked.
ַa a fonctionnי.
Because of you.
Grגce א toi.
No, Wade, because of you.
Non, Wade. Grגce א toi.
Stop, stop, stop!
Arrךte, arrךte !
Stop!
Arrךte !
Just let it happen, okay?
Accepte ce qui arrive.
I guess my heart was finally in the right place.
J'ai enfin eu le cur א la bonne place.
That riddle is so fucked up.
C'est ridicule, cette יnigme.
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
Je suis dיsolי.
Don't be. Don't be.
Ne le sois pas.
I've been trying to make this happen for a while.
Je souhaitais חa depuis un moment.
Please, just don't leave me.
Mais je t'en prie, reste prטs.
I don't wanna die without an audience.
Je veux mourir devant public.
We are not going anywhere.
On n'ira nulle part.
Oh, God, I hope the Academy is watching.
Mon Dieu, j'espטre que l'Acadיmie me voit.
Just rest, okay?
Laisse-toi aller.
Papa.
Papa.
Papa, can you hear me?
Papa, peux-tu m'entendre ?
Papa, can you find me in the night?
Papa, peux-tu me trouver Dans la nuit ?
Before I go...
Avant de partir...
Sorry, I got a bit more in me.
Pardon, je n'ai pas fini.
Domino.
Domino.
I want you to have my Adventure Time watch.
Je t'offre ma montre Adventure Time.
Turns out that I'm the lucky one.
C'est moi qui ai de la chance aprטs tout.
Thank you.
Merci.
Hey, Sabrina, the Teenage Witch.
Sabrina, l'apprentie sorciטre.
It has been a pleasure.
Content de t'avoir connue.
- Hi, Yukio. - Hi, Wade!
- Salut, Yukio. - Salut, Wade !
And you...
Et toi...
Chrome Bone.
Le chromי.
I haven't always been the best friend to you.
Je n'ai pas toujours יtי un bon ami pour toi.
But you've always been that to me.
Mais tu l'as toujours יtי pour moi.
So thank you.
Merci.
Say "fuck" for me.
Dis "foutoir" pour moi.
Just once. Come on, we'll do it together. It's no big deal.
Juste une fois. Allez, on le fera ensemble. Il n'y a rien lא.
Here we go. One, two, three.
On y va. Un, deux, trois.
Fuck.
Foutoir.
Wow! Enjoy hell, swamp mouth.
Ouah ! Tu iras en enfer avec ces gros mots.
And you, Cable.
Et toi, Cable.
You get back to your family. You tell 'em Wade says hi.
Va retrouver ta famille. Salue-la de ma part.
And promise me. Promise me one thing.
Et promets-moi une chose :
That you'll start judging people...
que tu jugeras les gens
not by the color of their skin, but by the content of their character.
non pas א leur couleur, mais א leur caractטre.
- Jesus. - R-Dog?
- Seigneur. - R-Dog ?
There you are. Hey!
Te voilא. Hי !
You're a superhero now, bubba.
Tu es devenu un superhיros.
Look.
ֹcoute-moi.
Family is not an F-word.
"Famille" n'est pas un gros mot.
All right?
D'accord ?
There's one out there for you.
Tu trouveras la tienne.
Just keep looking, okay?
N'arrךte pas de la chercher.
Guys, for a second there...
Les amis, pendant une seconde,
we made a pretty good team.
on formait une plutפt belle יquipe.
It's so hard to go.
C'est dur de vous quitter.
I just love being around you guys so much.
J'aime tellement votre compagnie.
So, so much.
Tellement.
No, I can feel it now. Here it comes, yeah.
Non, je le sens. Le moment est venu.
I feel the soul exiting the husk.
Je sens mon גme quitter cette enveloppe charnelle.
Yeah.
Oui.
Can you see it?
La voyez-vous ?
Do you see that beautiful bright light?
Voyez-vous cette belle lumiטre brillante ?
There it is.
Elle est lא.
That's the sun. Don't stare directly into that.
C'est le soleil. Il ne faut pas le fixer directement.
I just have a few final words.
Il me reste quelques mots א dire.
Woodpecker.
Pic-bois.
Gingivitis.
Gingivite.
Codswallop.
Balivernes.
Do You Want to Build a Snowman?
Je voudrais un bonhomme de neige.
Sorry I'm late.
Pardon du retard.
There was a bunch of handicapable children who were stuck in a tree.
Il y avait une bande d'enfants handi-capables coincיs dans un arbre.
- No.
- Non.
- But I did have to help a kid. - Yeah.
- Mais j'ai aidי un garחon. - Oui.
- He's got a terrible name. - It's just awful.
- Il a un nom affreux. - Atroce.
I tried to tell him.
J'ai voulu le lui dire.
Is this heaven?
C'est le paradis ?
It is now.
Ce l'est א prיsent.
I am so sorry.
Je suis navrי.
It's okay.
Ne t'en fais pas.
I missed you so much.
Tu m'as tant manquי.
What is it? What's wrong?
Qu'est-ce qui ne va pas ?
It's not time.
L'heure n'est pas venue.
What do you mean it's not time?
Comment חa ?
I'm here, I made it.
Je suis arrivי.
- You can't stay. - No, no, no.
- Tu ne peux pas rester. - Non.
I'm staying. I'm not going anywhere without you.
Je reste. Je n'irai nulle part sans toi.
It's okay.
ַa ira.
There's a time for us. It's just not now.
Notre heure viendra. Ce n'est pas encore le temps.
- They need you. - Who?
- Ils ont besoin de toi. - Qui חa ?
Your F-word.
Ton gros mot.
Why?
Pourquoi ?
You'll find out.
Tu verras bien.
It's all right. I'll be here.
ַa ira. Je serai juste ici.
I love you.
Je t'aime.
I know. I love you, too.
Je sais. Je t'aime aussi.
Now, go.
Pars.
Go on. Go, get out of here.
Allez, fiche le camp.
Go.
Vas-y.
Hey!
Hי !
Kiss me like you miss me, Red.
Embrasse-moi comme si je t'avais manquי.
Well, come here.
Approche, alors.
Don't fuck Elvis.
Ne couche pas avec Elvis.
- Don't fuck Colossus. - What?
- Ne couche pas avec Colossus. - Quoi ?
- Time to make the chimichangas. - 30 seconds.
- Ils vont bouffer du gיnיral K.O. - Trente secondes.
Hey. Been meaning to ask you...
Je voulais te demander,
what's with the creepy, dirty hobo bear?
c'est quoi, cet ours tout sale qui fait peur ?
It's my daughter's teddy bear.
C'est l'ours en peluche de ma fille.
Her name's Hope.
Elle s'appelle Hope.
What are you doing?
Que fais-tu ?
Somebody swiped right.
Quelqu'un a balayי א droite.
Tell me they got that in slow motion.
Dites-moi qu'on a filmי חa au ralenti.
You sacrificed yourself for me.
Tu t'es sacrifiי pour moi.
It would seem I...
On dirait bien que je...
Genuine, high-grade lead.
Du plomb de premiטre qualitי.
You time-sliding son of a bitch!
Mon enfoirי de voyageur dans le temps !
You did this for me?
Tu as fait חa pour moi ?
Wait. You can't go back.
Attends. Tu ne pourras plus rentrer.
You used the last of your fuel. What about your girl, your wife?
Tu n'as plus de carburant. Ta femme et ta fille, alors ?
Now, my family's safe. And I didn't do it for you.
Ma famille est en sretי. Je ne l'ai pas fait pour toi.
No, I'm gonna stick around for a while...
Je vais rester un bout de temps,
and make sure the world doesn't shit itself into oblivion.
m'assurer que la planטte ne disparaisse pas sous sa merde.
No. You did it for me.
Non. Tu l'as fait pour moi.
No, I didn't.
Pas du tout.
- You did. - I really didn't.
- Mais oui. - Mais non.
- Pretty sure you did. - No, I'm positive I didn't.
- Sr que oui. - Sr que non.
Fine. All right, let's flip a coin. Okay?
Tirons א pile ou face.
Heads, you did it for me. Tails, you did it for me.
Pile, tu l'as fait pour moi. Face, pour moi.
I'm not even gonna look, because you did it for me.
Je ne regarderai pas, car tu l'as fait pour moi.
Say it again.
Redis חa.
- He did it for me. - Jesus.
- Il l'a fait pour moi. - Seigneur.
- We must get the collar off. - Forget it. It's no use.
- Il faut enlever le collier. - Inutile.
These collars don't just come off.
Ces colliers ne s'enlטvent pas.
Wade.
Wade.
I have an idea.
J'ai une idיe.
No, no, no! Let's not do that. Please!
Non ! Pas חa. Je t'en prie !
I'd rather die of cancer. Let's just...
Je prיfטre mourir du cancer. Mieux vaut...
Oh, God! They do say the pen is grosser than the sword.
Mon Dieu ! C'est le plus dיgueu des stylos.
We need the code.
Il faut le code.
Try seven?
Essaie le sept.
Settle down, Captain Lucky.
Du calme, capitaine chance.
It's not gonna be one number.
ַa ne sera pas un seul chiffre.
God, that's lazy writing.
Les scיnaristes sont trop paresseux.
I still got it.
J'ai la touche magique.
Put that back in your prison wallet.
Remets חa dans ton portefeuille de prison.
I don't know how to thank you.
Je ne sais pas comment te remercier.
But I do know how to hug you.
Mais je sais te faire un cגlin.
- No. - Yes.
- Non. - Oui.
Here we go. Bring it in.
Allez. Approche.
Come on.
Viens lא.
Pelvis to pelvis.
Pubis contre pubis.
Let's go tip to tip.
Gland contre gland.
There we go. The kids call this docking.
Les jeunes appellent חa "le docking".
Is there a knife in my dick?
C'est un couteau contre ma bite ?
- There's a knife in your dick. - I'm just gonna back up now.
- C'est un couteau. - Je vais reculer.
- Yeah, yeah. - No need to go full Yentl.
- Oui. - Je tiens א mes parties.
Gonna pretend like that never happened.
Faisons comme si ce n'יtait pas arrivי.
Let's go home, Russell.
Rentrons א la maison, Russell.
All you dirty mutants are gonna rot in hell with the boy!
Vous tous, sales mutants, vous brlerez en enfer avec le petit !
Your souls are beyond redemption!
Vos גmes ne peuvent pas ךtre sauvיes !
Let's see your soul, perv!
Ni la tienne, pervers !
No, no! No! No more! We're better than that!
Non ! C'est fini ! On vaut mieux que חa !
We're better than him!
Mieux que lui !
No more senseless violence! No more bloodshed!
Finis, la violence insensיe et les carnages !
We'll let karma take care of him.
Le karma lui rיglera son compte.
The day of reckoning is here!
Le jour du jugement est arrivי !
I'm gonna miss him. He seemed great.
Il va me manquer. Il semblait chouette.
Courage, motherfuckers!
Le courage, mes salauds !
And karma, motherfucker.
Le karma, mon salaud.
I could hear you coming the last 30 seconds.
Je t'entendais venir depuis 30 secondes.
I could barely keep a straight face.
Je me retenais א peine de rire.
I want some more.
J'en veux encore.
I bet you do, Brown Panther.
Je n'en doute pas, Panthטre Brune.
We should leave before Fuckernaut wakes up.
Partons avant que le Flיau se rיveille.
Good call. You guys coming with us?
Bien vu. Venez-vous avec nous ?
No, we'll get the kids back to the mansion.
On raccompagne les jeunes au manoir.
Besides, we're X-Men.
Et puis, on est des X-Men.
No, you're X-People.
Non, vous ךtes des X-Personnes.
You're exhausting.
Tu es extיnuant.
I see what you did there. Puns.
Un petit jeu de mot. Je l'ai compris.
- Bye, Wade! - Bye, Yukio!
- Au revoir, Wade ! - Au revoir, Yukio !
What do you get when you take eight feet of chrome...
Qu'est-ce qu'on obtient en mךlant 2,4 mטtres de chrome,
one pinch of courage...
une pincיe de courage,
a cup of good luck...
une tasse de chance,
a dab of racism...
un soupחon de racisme,
a splash of diabetes...
un trait de diabטte
and a wheelbarrow full of stage four cancer?
et une brouette de cancer au stade quatre ?
Answer: a family.
Rיponse : une famille.
See? I didn't lie what kind of film this was.
Vous voyez ? Je n'ai pas menti sur le genre du film.
If there's anything you take away today...
Si vous devez retenir une chose,
other than the need to Google, "What the fuck is dubstep?"...
א part le besoin de chercher ce qu'est le dubstep,
it's that we all need to belong to someone.
c'est qu'on veut tous faire partie d'une tribu.
How something so small generates enough energy to reverse time is...
Comment un truc si petit produit assez d'יnergie pour inverser le temps...
Just fix it, Eleven, or I'll take it to the Genius Bar.
Rיpare-le, Eleven, sinon je l'apporte au Genius Bar.
Cable's gonna kill you when he finds out.
Cable te tuera s'il l'apprend.
Never heard of him.
J'ignore de qui tu parles.
Why do you think I'm helping him?
Pourquoi crois-tu que je l'aide ?
The Lord works in mysterious ways, don't I? A good day.
Les voies du Seigneur sont impיnיtrables. Comme les miennes. Bonne journיe.
Bye, Wade!
Au revoir, Wade !
Bye, Yukio!
Au revoir, Yukio !
That was probably a bad idea.
C'יtait probablement une mauvaise idיe.
What have we done?
Qu'avons-nous fait ?
I hope we sharpened the cream cheese spreader.
J'espטre qu'on a afftי le couteau א fromage.
I'll be right back!
Je reviens tout de suite !
We're definitely naming our kid Cher!
Notre enfant s'appellera Cher, c'est certain.
Peter!
Peter !
- X-Force! - Walk away! Just walk away!
X-Force !
- But we're X-Force! - Nope! We're not, there's no X-Force!
Mais on est la X-Force !
All right, well, this has been pretty scary!
Bon. ַa a יtי effrayant, cette histoire.
Wade, is that you?
Wade, c'est toi ?
I guess Stryker finally figured out how to shut you up.
Stryker a donc enfin compris comment te faire taire.
Hey! It's me! Don't scratch! Just cleaning up the timelines!
Salut ! C'est moi ! Ne me fais pas de mal ! Je rectifie la ligne du temps !
Love you!
Je t'aime !
Welcome to the big leagues, kid.
Bienvenue dans les ligues majeures.
You're welcome, Canada.
De rien, Canada.